<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debian on Moselog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/debian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debian on Moselog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 12:10:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 116</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2015/04/26/greenruby-116</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2015/04/26/greenruby-116</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;welcome-jessie:d9f4d66fbdcd986833b23a4199ad62c2&#34;&gt;Welcome Jessie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, right. Maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t care, but this saturday &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org/releases/jessie&#34;&gt;Jessie&lt;/a&gt; was
officially released. It&amp;rsquo;s the next stable version of debian, version 8.0, and
it&amp;rsquo;s great that it finally got out. Debian release cycles are certainly not as
fast as Ubuntu, but the stuff in there is more stable. And well, in my
personal case, I work in a place where everything is in debian wheezy and can
now finally get upgraded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually I have been using Ubuntu on my desktop for some time. The reason was
that I wanted to be able to help people to transition to linux, without being
overloaded with support. So I had to know how ubuntu work. But last year I
switched back to the original debian and I have been pretty happy about that.
There is less cruft and opinionated choices (no freaking unity as a default
window manager). And it&amp;rsquo;s pretty straightfoward in the install process. I
suspect even non-techies could give it a try (I know some that did).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 103</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2015/01/25/greenruby-103</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2015/01/25/greenruby-103</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-screens:d021634982f7dcb44b802e2a3d2040a7&#34;&gt;More Screens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, when I left Faria, I bought a laptop with a clear purpose. I
wanted to have on linux the same screen experience that I had with the macbook
pro connected to 2 thunderbolts. So I got an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asus.com/us/Notebooks_Ultrabooks/ASUS_ZENBOOK_UX301LA/&#34;&gt;asus UX301L&lt;/a&gt; plus 2
&lt;a href=&#34;http://accessories.ap.dell.com/sna/productdetail.aspx?c=au&amp;amp;cs=audhs1&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;redirect=1&amp;amp;s=dhs&amp;amp;sku=210-40773&#34;&gt;Dell screens U2713HM&lt;/a&gt; who supports a 2560x1440 resolution. The laptop in itself
is amazing, dazzling fast, and all worked well with an ubuntu install. This
was not cheap but that was a while I didn&amp;rsquo;t spend anything on hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggled a bit to find the proper connectors so I could enable the extra
large resolution on connected screens. I ended up using the mini-hdmi
connector plus a mini-display port converter to DVI for the second one. And
finally it worked last week. I had to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arunviswanathan.com/node/53&#34;&gt;force the resolution in xrandr&lt;/a&gt; and
now I have a damn huge double display for a total of 7680x1440. What a blast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;debian-i3wm-and-urxvt:d021634982f7dcb44b802e2a3d2040a7&#34;&gt;Debian, i3wm and urxvt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well this is an old story. Some time ago I switched from debian + fvwm2/ion to
ubuntu + cinnamon just because I had to know about it. The goal was to be able
to convince my wife (and some other non-techies) to switch to ubuntu. But I
had to know how it worked on a daily basis. And it was a success for most of
it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 years ago at Faria I was given a mac. Well, it was good to know a bit more
about it, my mac knowledge was dating from system 6.7 time. But if the
hardware is really good, the OSX experience didn&amp;rsquo;t really satisfy the geek
that was deep inside me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got back into a team that is deeply attached to pure linux traditions,
when I joined Gandi. I now switched back to a debian jessie with &lt;a href=&#34;https://i3wm.org/&#34;&gt;i3wm&lt;/a&gt; on
my work laptop. Wow this feels good to be back to such a rude but flexible
environment. As a matter of fact all went perfectly well and all the tricks I
knew 10 years ago are still very valid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also took that occasion to get back into urxvt, for my terminal emulator.
It&amp;rsquo;s a very badly documented over-powerful tool. But when you get the grasp on
it, possibilities are much more satisfying than with gnome-terminal. I&amp;rsquo;m still
working on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mose/rcfiles/blob/master/.Xdefaults&#34;&gt;my configuration&lt;/a&gt; to match few features that gnome terminal had
(like font resizing, clipboard management). The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mose/rcfiles/blob/master/.urxvt/ext/notification&#34;&gt;notification plugin&lt;/a&gt;,
combined with &lt;a href=&#34;http://knopwob.org/dunst/index.html&#34;&gt;dunst&lt;/a&gt;, gives amazing results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels good to be back into the cave. To mark this change, I didn&amp;rsquo;t shave
for 3 months so now I&amp;rsquo;m really bearded like the old-fashioned linux bears.
Muhaha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: no worry, I&amp;rsquo;m still fullstack at heart and I still love ruby!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>