<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcast on Mose Bla</title>
    <link>http://log.mose.com/tags/podcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcast on Mose Bla</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 09:10:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://log.mose.com/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Geeky podcasts</title>
      <link>http://log.mose.com/2013/02/10/geeky-podcasts</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2013 09:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://log.mose.com/2013/02/10/geeky-podcasts</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when doing some mechanical operation on my home workstation, involving repetitive action or something requiring low level of attention (like sorting mails, lurking on irc, updating a distro, …), I like to put the headset and listen to stuff. But I never had any taste for music, I prefer listening to people that talk about some interesting topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began this when starting working with rails, because that was a great flow of information, that had various sources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubyrogues.com&#34;&gt;http://rubyrogues.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://rubyshow.com&#34;&gt;http://rubyshow.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://learn.thoughtbot.com/podcast&#34;&gt;http://learn.thoughtbot.com/podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ruby5.envylabs.com&#34;&gt;http://ruby5.envylabs.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All was good and then I checked out podcast clients for my environment (linux with ubuntu) and I found out &lt;a href=&#34;http://gpodder.net&#34;&gt;http://gpodder.net&lt;/a&gt; which is exactly the kind of software I like. I does not much but what it does is well done. The website is a nice optional addition, only focused on podcasts and has a nice simple design and is free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install gpodder
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I discovered a few other podcasts for hackers, or oriented towards science and knowledge. And I removed the rss feed I had in my thunderbird for listening to some French-speaking radio shows (like la-bas si j&amp;rsquo;y suis).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website makes possible to publish your subscription list, here is my list of very geeky selection:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gpodder.net/user/mose/subscriptions&#34;&gt;https://gpodder.net/user/mose/subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>