<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Moselog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mose.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Moselog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 22:10:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.mose.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 174</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/06/05/greenruby-174</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/06/05/greenruby-174</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scarcity-and-abundance:18c51e5740969f01b50a58d17ac773ca&#34;&gt;Scarcity and abundance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may remember, this newsletter is using the generous free plan from
Mailchimp. But it has limits. Only 2000 emails ca subscribe to that
newsletter. It&amp;rsquo;s already a great gift, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it&amp;rsquo;s a good
business calculation for them. Now GreenRuby reaches 1915 subscriptions. Which
means we need to address that so pervasive concept of scarcity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can remember when it shifted. With the first web pages in 96. When tables
were introduced in HTML, then it became less obvious how to recreate something
you saw, and having the possibility to browse the source of a page gives you
the exact recipe on how it&amp;rsquo;s made. So you can copy from it. I think open
source would not have had such a large adoption if there was not that idea
with the HTML, that you need to have access to the source to learn, reproduce
and improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, it made even more obvious one of the key aspects of the internet age: by
dematerializing market goods (ie. with introduction of softwares), they became
reproducible at a cost that is marginal enough to be forgotten (yeah,
bandwidth and storage are not free, for sure). When you give it to someone,
you still have it. Not like that glass of beer. It placed us in an awkward
paradigm, the world of abundance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been so many efforts to artificially bend the internet to a world
of scarcity again. See, without scarcity, there is no economy as we know it.
There is another kind of economy, though, but the big guys that lead the old
one are not ready to let it go. For the old economy to work, things have to be
scarce. Otherwise there is no competition to obtain commodities, no motivation
to work like crazy to push forward the progress of production. In abundance
economy, also known as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gift_economy&#34;&gt;gift economy&lt;/a&gt;, people get less likely to be
controlled and they don&amp;rsquo;t want to work hard, they want pleasure and
satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I see the efforts made to control a resource that is naturally
abundant, by using the tools of law, copyright laws, patents, and all that
kind. I can&amp;rsquo;t help thinking about the abundance of material goods.
Technological progress, after war, promised some kind of abundant society.
Work would be automated so we would have less and less to work and just enjoy
the benefit of the global growth of humanity in taming the material world.
Well, we are far from it, and I&amp;rsquo;m instinctively convinced that it&amp;rsquo;s by design.
And it makes me sad. People still need jobs, society won&amp;rsquo;t provide for them.
There is nothing like common goods in that humanity. And now human compete
with machine for jobs, whereas they should have been allies. Sad, really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this led me quite far away from my initial topic: we got limited seats for
this newsletter, so we&amp;rsquo;ll do it 2 ways. First, I will send a mail to all
people that never click on any links, ask them if they want to stay there.
Then after a time I will unsubscribe the ones that stay silent and inactive.
That could skim some 300 people maybe. At the rate it goes, that can buy us
some 6 months, at the current rate of newcomers each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the subscription will be closed, unless I setup another publication
system, self-hosted. We don&amp;rsquo;t really need a fully-blown solution like
mailchimp to be totally honest. They do bit efforts to have mail servers that
are compliant with various anti-spam techniques, and this is a great thing.
But I bet I should be able to match it on a self-hosted server that would cost
me less than $10 a month. It would have no limit, at least. Maybe at that time
I will open some kind of donation program. Actually I already pay for the
hosting but I use my servers for other usages so it&amp;rsquo;s only a small fraction.
And honestly I could even host GreenRuby web pages on github pages for free.
But I would not have access to the logs for analytics and would need to setup
some piwik because I can&amp;rsquo;t cope with the idea of using GA. Or, I just don&amp;rsquo;t
care about traffic metrics. That&amp;rsquo;s tempting. But I got lost in my train of
thoughts here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bottom line is: we won&amp;rsquo;t get trapped by scarcity. Muahahaha. But feel free to
send me feedbacks on this topic if you have any thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 173</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/05/29/greenruby-173</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/05/29/greenruby-173</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;greenruby-irl-and-remote-meetup:cb0f8bc8c9864210771f601228a96c48&#34;&gt;GreenRuby IRL and Remote meetup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I posted a link about &lt;a href=&#34;http://remotemeetup.com/&#34;&gt;Remote Meetups&lt;/a&gt;, but, as it sometimes
happens, it didn&amp;rsquo;t stop there. The basic principle was appealing to me. It&amp;rsquo;s
true that we don&amp;rsquo;t all live in the Bay area or in New York. Having high
quality speakers in meetups is hard when you live in a small city or a remote
country. And this is exactly what that initiative tries to address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I jumped in and had some talk with Franze. The result is that the GreenRuby
meetup we will have this friday will also be remote. Some people will &lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.kktix.cc/events/grg-001&#34;&gt;attend
physically&lt;/a&gt;, some people will &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bigmarker.com/remote-meetup/Green-Ruby-Meetup-001&#34;&gt;come virtually&lt;/a&gt; using the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bigmarker.com/communities/remote-meetup&#34;&gt;Bigmarker&lt;/a&gt; platform on the RemoteMeetup account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those events usually are based on a format including a presentation followed
by interactions. My plan is to go nuts and try a full-social format, with no
presentation at all, jumping directly to the interactions. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be
highly experimental and may lead to failure, but it certainly won&amp;rsquo;t kill any
kitten in the process so I think we are safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mix between physical and remote event is the challenging part. We may try
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bigmarker.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/203332009-Attending-and-Hosting-Webinars&#34;&gt;usage of mobile phones&lt;/a&gt; to make local people become remote
participants (but it seems to be IOs only for now). I will get an iPad ready
for easier floating access, that can be fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are welcome to join, either online or irl. I heard &lt;a href=&#34;https://gandi.net&#34;&gt;Gandi&lt;/a&gt;, the
physical host and my employer, is going to fill up the fridge with hundred of
various beverages and won&amp;rsquo;t mind us to help reduce that quantity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 172</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/05/22/greenruby-172</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/05/22/greenruby-172</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-greenruby-meetup:0abecea4184e3afb12db751a6fc46d11&#34;&gt;First GreenRuby Meetup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently Gandi moved to a much bigger office in Neihu, Taipei. And I got
permission to use the space to organize events. We got a great space, sound
system with wireless mikes, a beamer for presentations. So, if you are in
Taipei, feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.kktix.cc/events/grg-001&#34;&gt;join us on wednesday next week&lt;/a&gt;.  I will try to
make it a remote meetup, and give more details next week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 170</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/05/08/greenruby-170</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/05/08/greenruby-170</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-s-the-fault-of-the-bike:5828fd4de747cabcdfd7abec8b5b8468&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the fault of the bike&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, in the last two weeks I get short in links gathered on our slack pinned
list. Usually I&amp;rsquo;m reading various RSS feeds while commuting, and I post them
on slack, for later one pinning them. Then I have a script in go that will
grab all the pinned url, and remove the pins at the moment I use and check
them for inclusion in the publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But 2 weeks ago, I decided to change my habits and go to the office by bike.
It&amp;rsquo;s a 30 minutes ride, and it&amp;rsquo;s very good. But then hare we are: no no way to
check RSS on the phone. I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to find another trick. Because I
won&amp;rsquo;t quit the biking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 168</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/04/25/greenruby-168</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/04/25/greenruby-168</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nanoservices:037dc3f5d87e2e1488613d254aa9c717&#34;&gt;Nanoservices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That link to &lt;a href=&#34;http://shoutcloud.io&#34;&gt;Shoutcloud&lt;/a&gt; made me laugh and then made me think.
It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time I see some micro-service publicly available. 2 years
ago there was some talk about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/news/2014/05/nano-services&#34;&gt;nano-services as an antipattern&lt;/a&gt;.
But when you push the logic a little further, and at a very large scale, maybe
it&amp;rsquo;s a projection of what the future will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine our software totally destructured, calling functions taht are stored
on the net, using some load balanced worldwide environment. We already do that
with CDNs. Javascript next Modules proposals will go in that direction as
well. But what is a method call in a program that we know today could become a
service call of an external globally available function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all we always write the same code. How many time did you write a regexp
for &lt;a href=&#34;http://emailregex.com/&#34;&gt;email pattern validation&lt;/a&gt;? The RFC 822 and 5322 are nasties,
yeah. If we had no latency consideration, I would gladly delegate various
pieces of code to a specialized service. But latency, is it really an issue
now? We work more and more with async code, with queues and messages. What
seems heretic for our current legacy standards would not seem that foolish in
a slightly different context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So technically, I suppose nanoservices are a possible future. I even think
it&amp;rsquo;s a requirement for scaling any kind of agent-based architecture. Machine
learning will be much better off by just registering maps to knowledge than
knowledge itself. But I wonder about the economical side of things. The old
capitalist market economy is already stretching its reach far beyond its
original statement with immaterial economy. The totally destructured
immaterial one will certainly propose an interesting challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 166</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/04/10/greenruby-166</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/04/10/greenruby-166</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-again:16e33c9f1a3f0ada66ffc6cd616986d9&#34;&gt;Go again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s years that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to do something real with go. I mean, it is a
very attractive language with quite a special workflow and toolbox. From time
to time I write some small script for keeping contact with that language. Last
week I made &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/greenruby/slackpin/blob/master/pins.go&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; to list links pinned in our Greenruby
slackroom to prepare the letter, So I can open them all at once to check them
in my browser. With time passing, seems that Go now has a really complete
collection of libraries for a lot of usages. I think I will have push a little
the slack api soon, and maybe do some real go coding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 165</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/04/03/greenruby-165</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/04/03/greenruby-165</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;aprils-lame-fools:04ce5954ad800128a33af7a0330e1817&#34;&gt;Aprils lame fools&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there is nothing I hate more than pranks. It&amp;rsquo;s just another way to
bully someone else. Even innocent pranks are having victims. Single out the
one that fall for it to make laugh the ones that don&amp;rsquo;t. Well, I may very well
be a boring fellow. Or it&amp;rsquo;s just that, working so much with information
management, any perversion of it seems off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then on april fools day, so much goes wrong. The net becomes unreliable.
So lame. But I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s the reason there are not that many news
articles this week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 164</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/03/27/greenruby-164</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/03/27/greenruby-164</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;kik-the-fuss:2a9c5ad01254a64b6911e087d156ed08&#34;&gt;kik the fuss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some noise last week about npm, coming from &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@azerbike/i-ve-just-liberated-my-modules-9045c06be67c#.evxywifiu&#34;&gt;that
article&lt;/a&gt;. It merely revealed that various open source
organization are privately held by some individuals and they can either be
pressured or take weird decisions. Honestly I consider this incident
anecdotal. It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time such thing happens. One guy just happened
to be very vocal and pissed off about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it carried various threads of discussion on Twitter and elsewhere, in a
huge controversy. There were many points raised. NPM has thousands and
thousands of packages, and many of them are just a few lines of utility
library, so it was a good occasion for some to point out that you should
reduce your number of dependencies. Others pointed out that namespacing could
help prevent such situation, like it&amp;rsquo;s done in docker or in go (having
username/somelib instead of somelib) following the github convention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, it appears that open source is gaining its traction from being
free of any legal duty. Or at least there is no formal contracting, no
by-laws, on committees or advisors. People do how they feel in the limits of
some very simple basic licensing rules. Some organization provide a more
structured legal asset but they usually are on the side and purposed for
channeling money management, not necessarily patents and intellectual
property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My opinion is that this kind of friction between businesses and open source is
going to happen more and more. But I wonder how it&amp;rsquo;s going to turn out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 163</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/03/20/greenruby-163</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/03/20/greenruby-163</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-rant-this-week:db8cdf835bd9f38d6f3130fd681dae2e&#34;&gt;No rant this week&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well it&amp;rsquo;s not the first time. I just don&amp;rsquo;t feel inspired. So I better shut up
rather than writing useless rant. It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to fill up space with
meaningless content. But I&amp;rsquo;m not doing that ever. I only speak out when I have
something to say. And yes, I&amp;rsquo;m very comfortable to contradict myself by
writing a useless rant. This is the beauty of the human being: our ability to
abstract makes possible all sort of paradoxes. Wait, is it related to
abstractions? hmm, This is a great topic for my day-dreaming in the subway.
Oh, damn I&amp;rsquo;m late. Cya all and have a good week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 162</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/03/13/greenruby-162</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/03/13/greenruby-162</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-adwar:debed575b05619529113f9bc1dd797c9&#34;&gt;the Adwar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I got 2 links that explore both sides of the adwar. The war on
advertisement exists on the web since it became popular enough to attract
advertisers. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/fivefilters/block-ads/wiki/There-are-no-acceptable-ads&#34;&gt;There are no acceptable ads&lt;/a&gt; takes the side of the users,
while &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2016/03/never-ending-story-ad-blockers&#34;&gt;A Never-Ending Story On Ad-Blockers&lt;/a&gt; seems to defend and
advise the publishers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some media already have blocked the blockers. It&amp;rsquo;s forbidden to escape ads?
This position may appear not to be sustainable. And pushing towards content
sponsoring could have really bad ill effects on the long term. Is there any
escape? Honestly I have to say that I&amp;rsquo;m partial in that debate. I don&amp;rsquo;t like
ads on what I read, and I don&amp;rsquo;t like ads on what I publish. I even go edit my
/etc/hosts with some custom domains to resolve to 127.0.0.1 sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it there was to take sides, I would say advertiser, go to hell. But I&amp;rsquo;m a
realist. They won&amp;rsquo;t go away. We live in a society where shit has to be bought.
Yes even if you don&amp;rsquo;t need it. Otherwise the system will collapse. That&amp;rsquo;s how
things are. I get some crazy dreams about some &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basic_income&#34;&gt;basic income&lt;/a&gt;
system, currently &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Basic_income_around_the_world&#34;&gt;in experiment&lt;/a&gt; in various places over the
globe. Such setup would defeat part of this situation, even if it would have
border effects that are unpredictable. But that would not change much for the
big corpo, it would only save the small people. Hmm. Sounds good enough to me,
I won&amp;rsquo;t lie.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 160</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/02/28/greenruby-160</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/02/28/greenruby-160</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-tests-and-documentation:329bfb00efd0c1fb86f4a0195e637cef&#34;&gt;About tests and documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This aspect of development, called Documentation, is the source of various
frustrations. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to get do it, but why? My feeling is that it&amp;rsquo;s like
testing. When you begin your craft as a coder, all what matters is the code.
It&amp;rsquo;s only after some iterations that some non-code aspects come back bite you
in the neck. Like, huho, now that I need to refactor, I really should use
something that tells me if all still works. Tests become an early necessity to
anyone who knows that kind of truth. If you wait until the end of a coding
cycle to write those, the task is huge and it cuts you from your productivity
cycle. Write them early, along the flow, is way easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think documentation follows the same pattern. So many software projects
are badly documented because this aspect is postponed until it&amp;rsquo;s needed. Means
at release stage. In early stages, you work on a prototype and you don&amp;rsquo;t need
to explain how things work or are supposed to work. And when it&amp;rsquo;s released,
there is usually some other task waiting and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to stop everything to
get back and document things properly. It may be a flaw in the agile process,
but it may also be a feature: if you don&amp;rsquo;t document along the way, you won&amp;rsquo;t
document much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally I try to consider the documentation of any of the source code I
write as one of the first tasks. There are various tricks that can help in
that perspective, like &lt;a href=&#34;http://tom.preston-werner.com/2010/08/23/readme-driven-development.html&#34;&gt;readme-driven development&lt;/a&gt;, or including the doc
inside the code with &lt;a href=&#34;http://yardoc.org/&#34;&gt;yarddoc&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://ilyabylich.svbtle.com/apipie-amazing-tool-for-documenting-your-rails-api&#34;&gt;apipie&lt;/a&gt;, or coupling
documentation with tests with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.relishapp.com/zipmark/rspec-api-documentation/docs/generate-html-documentation-from-test-examples&#34;&gt;rspec&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zipmark/rspec_api_documentation&#34;&gt;RSpec API Doc
Generator&lt;/a&gt;. But honestly I prefer edited documentation that can follow
a structure that is thought as documentation rather than merely an automated
output of some code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are various tools to organize edited documentation, like
&lt;a href=&#34;https://readthedocs.org/&#34;&gt;ReadTheDoc&lt;/a&gt; which is in python. Another project appeared last week from
the guys at Pluralsight named &lt;a href=&#34;http://tutorials.pluralsight.com/faq/&#34;&gt;hack.guide()&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s a community project
but actually being totally open sourced, I was thinking the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/pluralsight/guides-cms&#34;&gt;documentation
building CMS&lt;/a&gt; they made could pretty much fill the gap of a
light-weight RTD, with the benefits of having a UI for editors. Too bad we
don&amp;rsquo;t have anything like this in ruby (or do we?).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 159</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/02/21/greenruby-159</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/02/21/greenruby-159</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;timezones-are-outdated:d102e5698628cd2679575c8fc001deb8&#34;&gt;Timezones are outdated&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I checked out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/worldviews/wp/2016/02/12/the-radical-plan-to-destroy-time-zones-2/&#34;&gt;The radical plan to destroy time
zones&lt;/a&gt;, which proposes to adopt UTC worldwide. It goes even
further in proposing a change in our calendar for adopting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hanke-Henry_Permanent_Calendar&#34;&gt;Hanke-Henry
Permanent Calendar&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not the first time people propose change
in our western gregorian calendar system (which is almost 500 yearsold), but
it&amp;rsquo;s quite not easy to get anything adopted.
Still, we developers consider Timezones as one of our nightmares. When we get
to our senses we put everything we can in UTC, but there is always the need to
get time &amp;lsquo;local&amp;rsquo; at some point. I have honestly little hope that UTC become
the worldwide standard, but, hey, we always can dream, right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 158</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/02/14/greenruby-158</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/02/14/greenruby-158</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-thin-line-between-chaos-and-harmony:430ae6e4341a8c2a323bbff1cdaa06fc&#34;&gt;The thin line between chaos and harmony&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long road of my developer life I had the chance to experience a very
wide variety of organizational models. The most pleasant was in the context of
very large open source projects, where actions are not planned but still
organized, and things fall in their place seemingly naturally. Of course there
is nothing natural in that. There is a category of people, that can be called
catalysts, working as gardeners and building the pathways to collaboration.
But because there is no predefined hierarchy, I thought chaos had some
virtues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other hierarchical models, there is so much waste following the rule rather
than its essence. It&amp;rsquo;s like there was an abstraction layer for efficiency and
the staff follows the abstraction, paying no respect to the efficiency.
Because after a time the set of rules is not making sense anymore. The
environment moves fast and habits are hard to change. It&amp;rsquo;s taking long time
for an organization to change its own internal rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I also have seen non-hierarchical model totally fail. When you try to
apply an open-source kind of organization inside a company, it cannot be done
half-way, but it cannot be done fully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example the volatility of contributors is an essential part of the
open-source organization model. Things are working the way they do because
people are free to leave and join at will, or stop working when they decide.
This is totally different in a company, even if you can get some
approximation, leaving and joining is a more complicated process, and has a
different set of motivations. And let&amp;rsquo;s not talk about the freedom to stop
working at will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This single factor leads the free-formed communities to get various incentives
for contributors to feel good about their interaction in the community. The
ones that don&amp;rsquo;t play well along other people just end up either in a
leadership position because they are geniuses, or just leave because they
don&amp;rsquo;t fit in. Or they stay and kill the project because everybody else leaves.
But most likely they are the reason why forks exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in a non-hierarchic company, those cowboys may end up hurting the whole
process of collaboration by capturing some processes, getting very good at
them, and give hell to everybody else for a time, under the privilege of the
Power of the Bottleneck. It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to get those people to share knowledge
because their position depends on it. If nothing is done, the situation will
become uneasy and awkward at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly in that type of situation, if there is some power in place to
mitigate this danger, all can be good and well. But from my experience such
power is hard to come by. Especially if the non-hierarchic aspect of the
organization depends on him/her/it. Maybe there is some way to have some kind
of catalyst role, but where I have seen such role in a company, it was
informal and not an official position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s too bad because I would love to experience again some real collective
intelligence in the workplace the same way I have experienced it in some open
source communities. I think maybe there are some companies out there that are
doing that well, but most of the time it&amp;rsquo;s not going to be structural. Most
likely it will come from a specific set of people that do real good in
collaboration. I still wait to see a company that includes in its genetic
code, in its fundamental principle, the seeds that make it possible to be
efficient and still instinctive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 156</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/01/31/greenruby-156</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/01/31/greenruby-156</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-years-of-green-ruby:183ee6564ab7e32d81baa05c527bf345&#34;&gt;3 years of Green Ruby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, almost 3 years. &lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.org/grn-001.html&#34;&gt;Green Ruby #1&lt;/a&gt; was sent on feb 12th, 2013. Since
then, we sent 156 editions, one per week without discontinuation, including a
total of 5556 links. There is now 1691 subscribers to the newsletter. That&amp;rsquo;s
quite something, for a mail that was just sent to some friends at the
beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During all this time, things didn&amp;rsquo;t change that much. In july 2013 the code
was put on github and the process didn&amp;rsquo;t change much since then. I got a
Rakefile to build the letter from yaml files and there is no need to change
it. For the first 2 years Xenor was sending me some links by mail every weeks,
then in 2015 Tysliu got back in and we used git to get both of their
contributions. Later on, we got the slack channel where we throw between 10 to
30 links per weeks that I do my selection from. Nauman recently proved to be
the most prolific contributor on slack. (btw if you want to join our slack
group, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty open, just fire me an email).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still don&amp;rsquo;t have any business project behind this publication. We are just
a group of friends that like to keep in touch with the current trends, and
that like to share the result of our weekly workout with our fellow coder
brothers and sisters. Soon we will reach the limit of the free mailchimp usage
(at 2000 subscribers), and that will be an interesting time. We will then ask
people to unsubscribe if they don&amp;rsquo;t read the letter. Maybe registration will
be closed if we reach the hard limit. But there is no plan to become a
sustainable money-based adventure. So we&amp;rsquo;ll keep the cost to the minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel any gratefulness at all, pay it forward. Share your knowledge
around you. Publish more open source code. Hug a friend or a stranger. Be nice
and tolerant. Send some thank-you email to someone that published some open
source code that saved your day. Love is wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 155</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/01/24/greenruby-155</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/01/24/greenruby-155</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-under-engineering:fcbdcc9c124e7d704858d627998434f7&#34;&gt;The future of under-engineering&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently Marcelo told me, that&amp;rsquo;s weird, how we do 10% research and
specification, 40% implementation and 50% debugging in this industry. I&amp;rsquo;m more
used to 70% research and specification, 20% implementation and 10% debugging.
He was working in the hardhware industry for a while, and just came to a
service-based company. This is actually a very interesting remark and it
reminded me when I was in my twenties when I was working as a construction
worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was young there was no internet and I had a 10 years break from
computers. I had to take stupid jobs like working on construction sites for
low wages. After that I went to art school and later on I worked on building
sets for business shows. I have been shocked by the gap between those 2
worlds. When building a house, there is so much time spent writing plans,
thinking things in advance. While in the show-business construction pattern,
it was mostly about improvisation and managing inflexible time constraints,
with one-time-use construction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel there is the same gap in the software industry. Well it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly
the same for sure, but the paradigm feels alike. In service software
production, SaaS or ISP businesses, we tend to under-engineer the production.
There are perfectly legitimate reasons for that, the life-cycle of a platform
of service is quick, volatile and the value is not in the software asset but
in the customer-user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Agile organization model reinforces this pattern, by providing a
substitute to the early specifications, in the form of user experiences
description. All this is fine and good. For a time. But with years passing we
can see so many occurrences of &amp;lsquo;temporary&amp;rsquo; projects becoming indestructible
legacy monsters. It&amp;rsquo;s like there was some kind of tipping point where the
development should shift from under-engineered to well-engineered but it&amp;rsquo;s
rarely anticipated properly enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s pretty hard to address that kind of problem. Throwing away the early
instances is very costly, especially when the organization is shaped by a
fast-paced reactive production model. Introducing proper engineering at early
stages is also not a clever option, as the product has to adapt to the
service, which depends on a constant feedback loop with the users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the feeling that there is something missing. Like an evolution of agile
that could include seeds of later engineering. Some way to make possible to
start fast, and evolve in a solid and slower model later on without crisis or
disruption. This is the perspective that I think was missing in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/why-computer-programmers-need-to-stop-calling-themselves-engineers-already-2015-11&#34;&gt;that
article&lt;/a&gt; I cited on green ruby 145. But I don&amp;rsquo;t know the answer to
that problem. I suspect it will emerge by itself in the few next years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>