<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greenruby on Moselog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mose.com/tags/greenruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Greenruby on Moselog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 09:25:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.mose.com/tags/greenruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>bye bye Green Ruby</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2017/06/05/bye-bye-green-ruby</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 09:25:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2017/06/05/bye-bye-green-ruby</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m closing &lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.org&#34;&gt;Green Ruby&lt;/a&gt;. That newsletter, started on february 2013,
has been a self-imposed weekly duty for more than 4 years. I take a lot
of pride not to have missed one single week during those 225 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now that we decided, my friends and I, to put it to an end, there is an
interesting question popping up. What will happen with the list of 2,000 subscribers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s common knowledge that nowadays, when you don&amp;rsquo;t pay for a service, you are the product.
But honestly, I hate this statement, however relevant it may be.
It eludes any possibility of generosity, and any chance to enjoy a gift economy.
Open source software is an example of this.
You don&amp;rsquo;t pay for it, but by using it, you are not used as an asset or a resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as a symbolic gesture of rebellion, I decided that, by ending the publication,
I will delete the list of subscribers. Forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always felt raped when I subscribe to a service under a certain context, and then
the service provider gets acquired by another company and my account gets automatically
transferred. The contract changes, I have agreed to the initial setup, but why presume
I would automatically agree to any other context? This is the real annoyance in
that user-as-a-product thing. You are not considered as a thinking being anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the deletion of that list of email is a symbolic sacrifice. Why did you invest all
that time and effort during those 4 years then, will you ask me? Well, I was willing
to contribute to a common interest, out of generosity and love for my peers and friends.
Why should I need a money-related reason? Money kills the social link, it neutralize
the unmeasurable debt that we establish between each others as a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A society without generosity, is a society of isolated people. Gifts creates a feeling of debt,
that debt is a bond. If the gift is not personal, it relates you to a community.
Never forget about it. Pay it forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The virtues of transitions</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2017/05/31/the-virtues-of-transitions</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 20:25:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2017/05/31/the-virtues-of-transitions</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A collection of events occurred since my last post. I was really hoping to
get some deep dive into writing more about collective intelligence, in the background.
But various things came and distracted me from that initial trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hubot-revival:195c338923f21c367264a5b5fb00e8a9&#34;&gt;Hubot revival&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, there has been a revival of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/github/hubot&#34;&gt;Hubot project&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote a bunch of
plugins for that chatbot for internal usage at Gandi in the past year. I have been poking
around in the community complaining that it became some sort of abandonware. Issues on github
were not addressed, PR unanswered, irc was silent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then one day 3 weeks ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bkeepers&#34;&gt;bkeepers&lt;/a&gt; came up and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/github/hubot/blob/master/ROADMAP.md&#34;&gt;woke it up&lt;/a&gt;.
It appears that now Github has plan for this codebase. They want to include it in its products
more officially, says the rumor (nothing official yet). But it makes a lot of sense.
So then he gathered people that could be involved in the revival of the project. I was
contacted to join the core team. That&amp;rsquo;s what you get by nagging people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then it has been quite great to clean up backlog, re-examine old ideas, help setup
new process and tooling for community gardening. I never get tired to see how informal
communities can shape up and self-organize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quiting-is-not-a-bad-thing:195c338923f21c367264a5b5fb00e8a9&#34;&gt;Quiting is not a bad thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around the same time, I felt inspired by handing my resignation of my current job at Gandi.
There is nothing wrong with the job, and most reasonable people could argue that I&amp;rsquo;m just stupid.
But there are a combination of factors that led me to think I was not using my potential at
full capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on a large infrastructure as a sysadmin was great, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty hard to build new things
properly in the service industry. It&amp;rsquo;s always about contingency management, and reacting to the environment.
It&amp;rsquo;s more about doing the fireman than the gardener. Well, honestly, I think it&amp;rsquo;s a question of intent
and culture and that could have been addressed. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t see any hint that could let me think this
environment would become intentional about gardening anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, out of the blue, I left. I chose a moment where there was no crisis, no trouble, no real reason
to quit except a strong feeling that it was time to move on. That way, transition is painless, there
is no frustration involved. I hate conflicts. My advice: never wait the burn out to make your move out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;green-ruby-end-of-life:195c338923f21c367264a5b5fb00e8a9&#34;&gt;Green ruby end of life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mood of transitionning, this week I proposed that we close the &lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.org&#34;&gt;Green Ruby&lt;/a&gt; adventure.
For some months Xenor has taken over the publication process. But he&amp;rsquo;s himself bunt out a bit.
So after 4 years of publication, it&amp;rsquo;s time to close this properly and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That weekly links collection was a fun exercise. And I&amp;rsquo;m really happy to have refused any business
side track on this operation, it would have been much harder to close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-next:195c338923f21c367264a5b5fb00e8a9&#34;&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I could stay funemployed for a while (that&amp;rsquo;s the proper term, right?). I&amp;rsquo;m planning
to look around, play with techs, talk with friends, hold on any decision to engage in anything.
It&amp;rsquo;s time to re-assess my roadmap. This is what is great in transitions.
By losing contact with the ground, you can feel the direction of the wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I will get back to entrepreneurship, and setup some business venture. Maybe I will freelance for a while.
Maybe I will find a context in a company where I feel comfortable contributing. But honestly I have no clue.
And yet, this feels great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-back-to-old-friends:195c338923f21c367264a5b5fb00e8a9&#34;&gt;Getting back to old friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first days after my decision to renounce my day job, I got back in contact with a lot of old friends.
Transitions have that side effect that you have to re-evaluate your environment, your network, your values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting into a full-time job doesn&amp;rsquo;t prevent that, of course, but you cannot give the same attention.
The center of gravity of an employed person is static. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m floating, I have to dedicate much more
attention to my environment. And it&amp;rsquo;s an excellent thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will certainly have occasion to talk about my adventures very soon. Maybe I will force myself to write more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GreenRuby IRL and Remote meetup</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/05/29/greenruby-irl-and-remote-meetup</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/05/29/greenruby-irl-and-remote-meetup</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I posted a link about &lt;a href=&#34;http://remotemeetup.com/&#34;&gt;Remote Meetups&lt;/a&gt;, but, as it sometimes
happens, it didn&amp;rsquo;t stop there. The basic principle was appealing to me. It&amp;rsquo;s
true that we don&amp;rsquo;t all live in the Bay area or in New York. Having high
quality speakers in meetups is hard when you live in a small city or a remote
country. And this is exactly what that initiative tries to address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I jumped in and had some talk with Franze. The result is that the GreenRuby
meetup we will have this friday will also be remote. Some people will &lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.kktix.cc/events/grg-001&#34;&gt;attend
physically&lt;/a&gt;, some people will &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bigmarker.com/remote-meetup/Green-Ruby-Meetup-001&#34;&gt;come virtually&lt;/a&gt; using the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bigmarker.com/communities/remote-meetup&#34;&gt;Bigmarker&lt;/a&gt; platform on the RemoteMeetup account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those events usually are based on a format including a presentation followed
by interactions. My plan is to go nuts and try a full-social format, with no
presentation at all, jumping directly to the interactions. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be
highly experimental and may lead to failure, but it certainly won&amp;rsquo;t kill any
kitten in the process so I think we are safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mix between physical and remote event is the challenging part. We may try
the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bigmarker.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/203332009-Attending-and-Hosting-Webinars&#34;&gt;usage of mobile phones&lt;/a&gt; to make local people become remote
participants (but it seems to be IOs only for now). I will get an iPad ready
for easier floating access, that can be fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are welcome to join, either online or irl. I heard &lt;a href=&#34;https://gandi.net&#34;&gt;Gandi&lt;/a&gt;, the
physical host and my employer, is going to fill up the fridge with hundred of
various beverages and won&amp;rsquo;t mind us to help reduce that quantity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First GreenRuby Meetup</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/05/22/first-greenruby-meetup</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/05/22/first-greenruby-meetup</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently Gandi moved to a much bigger office in Neihu, Taipei. And I got
permission to use the space to organize events. We got a great space, sound
system with wireless mikes, a beamer for presentations. So, if you are in
Taipei, feel free to &lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.kktix.cc/events/grg-001&#34;&gt;join us on wednesday next week&lt;/a&gt;.  I will try to
make it a remote meetup, and give more details next week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 years of Green Ruby</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/01/31/3-years-of-green-ruby</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/01/31/3-years-of-green-ruby</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, almost 3 years. &lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.org/grn-001.html&#34;&gt;Green Ruby #1&lt;/a&gt; was sent on feb 12th, 2013. Since
then, we sent 156 editions, one per week without discontinuation, including a
total of 5556 links. There is now 1691 subscribers to the newsletter. That&amp;rsquo;s
quite something, for a mail that was just sent to some friends at the
beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During all this time, things didn&amp;rsquo;t change that much. In july 2013 the code
was put on github and the process didn&amp;rsquo;t change much since then. I got a
Rakefile to build the letter from yaml files and there is no need to change
it. For the first 2 years Xenor was sending me some links by mail every weeks,
then in 2015 Tysliu got back in and we used git to get both of their
contributions. Later on, we got the slack channel where we throw between 10 to
30 links per weeks that I do my selection from. Nauman recently proved to be
the most prolific contributor on slack. (btw if you want to join our slack
group, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty open, just fire me an email).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still don&amp;rsquo;t have any business project behind this publication. We are just
a group of friends that like to keep in touch with the current trends, and
that like to share the result of our weekly workout with our fellow coder
brothers and sisters. Soon we will reach the limit of the free mailchimp usage
(at 2000 subscribers), and that will be an interesting time. We will then ask
people to unsubscribe if they don&amp;rsquo;t read the letter. Maybe registration will
be closed if we reach the hard limit. But there is no plan to become a
sustainable money-based adventure. So we&amp;rsquo;ll keep the cost to the minimum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel any gratefulness at all, pay it forward. Share your knowledge
around you. Publish more open source code. Hug a friend or a stranger. Be nice
and tolerant. Send some thank-you email to someone that published some open
source code that saved your day. Love is wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>150 weeks</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/12/20/150-weeks</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/12/20/150-weeks</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of a round number, this 150th edition of the Green Ruby Newsletter
is an occasion to see where we are. At this day there are 1,610 subscribers to
the email newsletter. The website has around 250 unique visits per day, which
mostly are RSS readers. Those are anecdotal numbers. As we have no intention
to monetize this initiative, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter that much. Soon we will enter
in the red zone in the amount of subscribers and we will need to push some
people out, those who forgot about the newsletter but also forgot to
unsubscribe. It will happen when we reach 1,800 (because Mailchimp is still
free under 2,000 subscribers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the whole life of the publication, we never missed one week. Last week,
thanks to Xenor, I even could have some rest. Now I&amp;rsquo;m better, flu never last.
We also have, for a couple of months, much more links contributions (thanks
Nauman Tariq). All in all, our model seems to have been pretty sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet at rubyconf</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/09/06/meet-at-rubyconf</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/09/06/meet-at-rubyconf</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Next friday we will be at &lt;a href=&#34;http://2015.rubyconf.tw/&#34;&gt;rubyconf Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;. Last year there was
around 300 attendees and there is 256 this year. But maybe there will be more
last minute registration, there is still some &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubytaiwan.kktix.cc/events/rubyconftw2015&#34;&gt;spots available&lt;/a&gt; (well
just 14 at this time). I will also be at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubytaiwan.kktix.cc/events/850d36b0&#34;&gt;pre-conf evening&lt;/a&gt; on
wednesday. Good time to meet if you are in Taiwan (we have 37 subscribers
there).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-stats-on-greenruby:5c5ed19a98630bcf79414a52c93d484e&#34;&gt;Some stats on greenruby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time I check an export of the subscribers list and do some stats
out of curiosity. As of today there are 1466 subscribers, and more than half
in the US (844) all the rest are in 88 other countries (most in India, UK,
France and Taiwan, in that order). In the US most people are from New-York,
just a little more than Los Angeles, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monticello,_Kentucky&#34;&gt;Monticello&lt;/a&gt; in Kentucky.
I wonder what there is so special in that city of less than 10k people. Maybe
that&amp;rsquo;s a geo-location glitch? If not, please someone tell me what there is in
that small and probably nice city. But if I had to bet, I would put my money
on the glitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every week there is a small number of new subscribers, especially during
summer. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t really read or if you don&amp;rsquo;t care that much, please
unsubscribe. I will certainly have to do some invitation to unsubscribe when
we will reach around 2000, because mailchimp if free of charge only under that
limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a lot of unaccounted subscribers to the RSS feed, which is the
most popular page on the website. But I don&amp;rsquo;t use feedburner or any kind of
tracking so I don&amp;rsquo;t really know. And I kind of like it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back on tweeting</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/07/26/back-on-tweeting</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/07/26/back-on-tweeting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really don&amp;rsquo;t like my phone. As an old timer I&amp;rsquo;m reluctant to trust my
android, but it would be the same on an iphone. The way applications require
access to the device, on android, is especially annoying and dishonest. They
make the slope slippery for the sake of saving seconds in adopting new apps,
but it&amp;rsquo;s leading to a total remission of users control over their devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But well, I still have a commute several times a week and I use my phone to
listen to various podcasts. But I recently configured some accounts and some
news readers, so I also can just do some links curation along the way. So I
suspect there will be more tweeting on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/greenrubist&#34;&gt;greenrubist&lt;/a&gt; account from
now on. It helps quite a lot when I want to gather links on every sundays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, nowadays, most of the links are actually gathered by xenor and tysliu,
but I always add a few on my own (especially the devops ones). Those 2 guys
are really doing an amazing demonstration of consistency. After 129 editions,
we still didn&amp;rsquo;t miss a single one week in our publication. It would not have
been possible without my buddies. Thanks so much for their contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby Better process and numbers</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/05/10/greenruby-better-process-and-numbers</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/05/10/greenruby-better-process-and-numbers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s a few weeks now that we are getting organized better, with Xenor and
Tysliu, on the preparation of this newsletter. The guys are now putting more
attention to the news gathering and preformatting the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/greenruby/grn-static/blob/master/newsletters/grn.yml&#34;&gt;yaml source file&lt;/a&gt;
that I use to generate the letter and the website. After
some time of practice, it is much better for me, as now I don&amp;rsquo;t spend 5 hours
each sunday anymore and I can manage the publication process in less than 2
hours. I still gather some extra links after the editors push their
contributions. Then I verify the links, the categories, edit the comments
sometimes, add dots at the ends of line, such tiny things. A huge thanks to
Xenor and Tysliu!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we have 1312 subscribers to the newsletter. Plus an unknown number of RSS
subscribers, maybe around 200. We get 250 visits per day on the website
(according to webalizer), and most of them come from rss readers of many
sorts. As the mailchimp is still free until we reach 2000, there is some
margin. When we reach 1600 I think I swill begin a cleaning campaign, to help
people that actually don&amp;rsquo;t read the letter to unsubscribe. I kind of like the
idea of throwing accounts away. Usually in web business, an account is an
asset and they are never thrown away. There is so much to be told about
numbers, and their reality, in our industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the reality about numbers is usually the consequence of the over
simplification required by marketeers. Things are never so simple as just a
single number. The technicians among us are always in pain when we need to
provide numbers, because they come with a strict definition of what they
count, and that definition is never respected by the people that just want to
use the number and put a sexy label on it. When we say &amp;lsquo;registered accounts&amp;rsquo;
they say &amp;lsquo;users&amp;rsquo;. Do you see the difference? Damn, I hate that system that
forces salesmen to become a liars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Ruby New Generation</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/03/29/green-ruby-new-generation</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/03/29/green-ruby-new-generation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had this week a very productive meeting with xenor and tysliu in our
preferred coffee shop. I explained more in detail my workflow and my quality
criterias. So now they can feed the links section and become the major editors
of Green Ruby. I Still keep the role of the publisher. I get their links, I
clean up stuff, verify freshness and reachability, remove superlatives, fix
category if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks a lot to Xenor and Tysliu (aka. Simon). Now they do the heavy
lifting and they are the reason why Green Ruby is still in your mailbox every
week.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to upgrade</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/03/15/time-to-upgrade</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/03/15/time-to-upgrade</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a long time I plan to re-engineer the way Green Ruby is produced. Last
week I told Xenor and Simon I was thinking about giving it a break. I&amp;rsquo;m not
that much anymore in the flow. Now my days are full ops and not that much dev.
But the guys didn&amp;rsquo;t want to let me stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we are going to organize things a little differently. Xenor and Simon,
which are full time rails developers, are going to handle the content more
extensively, and I will just manage the publication, plus some devops links.
So we need to get some tools ready to handle that new flow. Maybe, the time it
gets ready, we will take some time off. Maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I wish is to have a way to let more people jump in, too. Maybe we will
get inspiration in how &lt;a href=&#34;http://thechangelog.com/trello-as-a-cms/&#34;&gt;the changelog&lt;/a&gt; manages their news
flow. They based it on a &lt;a href=&#34;http://trello.com&#34;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s quite clever. By chance I
explored the trello API recently and I can tell it&amp;rsquo;s really good, very
suitable for custom automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, I will play lazy on the podcasts. I don&amp;rsquo;t think they are that much
interesting anyways, and all that copy-pasting is exhausting. When some
podcasts stands out of the crowd, I will rather feature it in this rant.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 years</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/02/01/2-years</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/02/01/2-years</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ghost:fba0bb1f68d1414085590cced7805ffa&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You certainly heard about it, this week there was a new huge Linux
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openwall.com/lists/oss-security/2015/01/27/9&#34;&gt;vulnerability on glibc&lt;/a&gt; revealed. Actually it was leaked by a stupid
communication agency few hours before it should have been announced. When such
big bug is discovered usually there is a small period of time where the news
spread into some limited circles. They keep it embargoed until major distro
vendors get patched packages ready. Well, it didn&amp;rsquo;t go that well this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This vulnerability is pretty nasty even if less obvious to exploit than
Heartbleed or shellshock, it&amp;rsquo;s probably in the same category. If you manage
servers that are vulnerable (LTS and stable, less up to date versions,
mostly), you better upgrade asap. When a bug gets its own name (this one is
called Ghost), it seems to be the sign it requires immediate attention. How
long is this trick going to work?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, as we talk about security, Hipchat users should read this (unnamed)
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hipchat.com/2015/02/01/hipchat-security-notice-and-password-reset/&#34;&gt;security notice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-years:fba0bb1f68d1414085590cced7805ffa&#34;&gt;2 years&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This edition is marking the 2 years anniversary of Green Ruby. For 104 weeks
I&amp;rsquo;ve been sending out this newsletter every week. Last week I had a discussion
with a friend, he was asking me what was my drive, and what was the reason of
my consistency. Well, there are various reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First there is the routine aspect. It&amp;rsquo;s like practicing Taichi or some kind of
exercise. It keeps the mind fresh, and in this context where things change
pretty fast, enforcing a weekly review gave me an overall feeling of symbiosis
with the wave of what&amp;rsquo;s going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second is the philosophy of it: this newsletter is a gift. The ruby world is
very business oriented. There is a lot of open source in there but still the
average spirit is based on a market economy. There are of course many
exceptions, I wanted to be one of them, and I believe a gift economy would be
more my thing. You get rich of what you give away, not always individually,
but most definitely collectively. I like that feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, this media keeps me in touch with a bunch of my friends. It&amp;rsquo;s like a
beacon that I send to the people I left behind when I left France to go live
in Taiwan. Or people I worked with in my past jobs in Taiwan, even. They don&amp;rsquo;t
often respond to it but I know they can perceive me through this weekly proof
of existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, there is the support from xenor and more recently from simon, which, by
sending me a few links each weeks, validate the need to keep things going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;trello-and-irc:fba0bb1f68d1414085590cced7805ffa&#34;&gt;Trello and irc&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as long as I remember, I always have been coding irc bots. In so many
languages. I suspect there is some aspect of this that appeals to me. Maybe
the creation of life-like pattern. Anyways, my last bot was of course in ruby,
I called it &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mose/cogbot&#34;&gt;cogbot&lt;/a&gt;, and is based on the great &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cinchrb/cinch&#34;&gt;cinch&lt;/a&gt; framework. It has
been sleepy for a while, since we were not using irc in Faria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Gandi is heavy irc user, and our recent experiments on trello gave me an
occasion to get cogbot out of the dust. As a matter of fact &lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com&#34;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; has a
really &lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com/docs/&#34;&gt;great API&lt;/a&gt;, and also supports webhooks. So I added a trello
listener to cogbot, and it was a lot of fun. Maybe next I will add some cards
creation and update features in that bot, but it requires some kind of users
management, which, on an irc bot, is not that trivial to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;free-your-code:fba0bb1f68d1414085590cced7805ffa&#34;&gt;Free your code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a side project? You should! Maybe the code you produce at work can
be generic enough? This is a call for you to consider freeing your code. Open
source community is plentiful but I know as a fact that 90% of the code that
could be shared is not shared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is something I noticed in my own code publication. Often in my work
there are constraints of time that lead to trade-offs and code quality is
never as good as I wish it was. By working on side projects, the pace is much
more relaxed and I can spend hours focusing on non productive efforts to make
my code better. Well, this is not to say that side project code is perfect,
but the environment of producing it brings another mindset. And after a while,
the code produced at work gets naturally more insightful because of this extra
practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a try, if you happen to have some free time. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have free
time, you&amp;rsquo;re doing something wrong. But that&amp;rsquo;s another story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 101</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/01/11/greenruby-101</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/01/11/greenruby-101</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1000-subscribers:dfd863a69df72c13bbe5f0b5d11c54ce&#34;&gt;1000 subscribers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the 100th Greenruby last week, we get the 1000th subscriber to the email
newsletter this week. Welcome George :) So for the occasion I refreshed the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://mose.cartodb.com/viz/6a4d431e-d6b7-11e3-8757-0e10bcd91c2b/embed_map&#34;&gt;subscribers map&lt;/a&gt; on cartodb. About half of the subscribers are in the US,
but there is a total of 73 countries represented, which is pretty neat. But
this is based on the ip used for subscribing, so it&amp;rsquo;s not totally accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fighting-logs-pollution:dfd863a69df72c13bbe5f0b5d11c54ce&#34;&gt;Fighting logs pollution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, on edition 82, I posted a link to my webalizer stats for the
greenruby website. Fatal mistake, I had referrers stats enabled and I got
somehow listed somewhere. The consequence was a lot of fake traffic with only
purpose to get links listed in my referrers section. After removing this
section from webalizer config, and moving the url, the fake traffic was still
there. Like a blind wave. This was pretty annoying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I began to take some drastic measures. Because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have referrers
anymore in my stats, I went to my apache logs (yes it&amp;rsquo;s an old server, still
running apache2) and fire up a:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;tail -5000 greenruby.org-access.log | cut -d&#39; &#39; -f11 | sort | uniq -c | sort -n
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This give me a nice view of the recent referrers. Fake ones are easy to
notice. And that the fake traffic was only coming from a handful of ips, so I
just made a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;iptables -A INPUT -s &amp;lt;ip&amp;gt; -j DROP
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result was radically efficient. Certainly I had less volume but it&amp;rsquo;s now
much cleaner. But it makes it clear that having clean volume stats for traffic
on your website is not that easy. There are a bunch of fake traffic sources
that you may not suspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-server-soon:dfd863a69df72c13bbe5f0b5d11c54ce&#34;&gt;New server soon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a new job 2 month ago at &lt;a href=&#34;http://gandi.net&#34;&gt;gandi&lt;/a&gt;, and there is some nice &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gandi.net/hosting/iaas&#34;&gt;VPS
hosting&lt;/a&gt; there. I can have a machine just for Green Ruby there. It can be
neat and open some options. Green Ruby website is still very static. Various
attempts to improve it with a search engine didn&amp;rsquo;t end up to something
concluding yet. Maybe this time it will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That also may be the occasion to build up a distribution system and move out
of mailchimp. I looked around and all I found was php based. So I will
probably just write my own ruby scripts, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mikel/mail&#34;&gt;mail gem&lt;/a&gt; looks great and the
rest is a question of configuring a postfix with correct &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linuxlasse.net/linux/howtos/Postfix_with_DKIM_%28OpenDKIM%29_and_SPF&#34;&gt;SPF and DKIM
setup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;je-suis-charlie:dfd863a69df72c13bbe5f0b5d11c54ce&#34;&gt;Je suis Charlie&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this tragedy that happened this Thursday in France impacts a lot of
people. Somehow, it perhaps impacts me more than the average. When I was
younger I went to art school to become a cartoonist, and finally I changed my
mind. But I knew the work of the victims of this slaughter. They were icons in
the French cartoon world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s really sad, first because this is murder, second because the irrational
impact it will have on society. This is crazy how a handful of brain-dead
punks can bend history. Now France is going to become even more paranoid. I
already was so uncomfortable when they began to send military with assault
rifles wander in the train stations in Paris. It&amp;rsquo;s not going to get better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 100</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/01/04/greenruby-100</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/01/04/greenruby-100</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week is the 100th edition of Green Ruby, it&amp;rsquo;s also the first one of 2015.
This week the &lt;a href=&#34;http://sixgun.org/episodes/lo370&#34;&gt;Linux Outlaws&lt;/a&gt; broadcasted their last show, and Rebecca
Watson left the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theskepticsguide.org/podcast/sgu/495&#34;&gt;Skeptics Guide to the Universe&lt;/a&gt;. Those are 2 podcasts that
I never list in the Green Ruby list (they are not really on topic) but I
rarely miss any of them. Too bad they leave. I thought about it too, but no, I
will stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, happy new year or, as we say in french: Bananier!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 100 weeks already I gathered those links and sent them to whoever wants
them. Every damn single week. Just for the fun of it. This is a kind of
personal kata, it keeps me in the loop. I just make my exercise in a way I can
share it. And my streak of never missing one week is a kind of personal
challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is now 971 subscribers to the mail newsletter, a whole lot of people
prefer to subscribe using the RSS feed, and the website has 8 or 9k visits per
month. But this is still a side project, with no business behind it. Just one
single guy and a couple of friends sharing the result of their weekly review
of the news of their craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as you can notice, the edito becomes a rant, and is going to get a bit
longer. For a while I was trying to keep it short just because it sits on the
top of the letter. What matters are the links and not the ranting. By moving
the blah blah at the bottom, I free myself from format constraints and can
unleash my writing desires. muahaha. Not that I have much to say. But you can
consider this new section of Green Ruby as the last screen displayed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chucklorre.com/index-bbt.php&#34;&gt;The
Big Bang Theory&lt;/a&gt;, where producers display some random thoughts, rants or
anecdote. You need to pause the video for being able to read them. Yeah I know
I could just blog like everybody else. But it&amp;rsquo;s just convenient for me to
include this writing in my weekly process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also improved formatting for text-only diffusion. There is still something
bugging me about the link tracking, which is mandatory when using the free
tier of Mailchimp service. I guess I will have to find a way around: either I
will get away from mailchimp, either I will find a sponsor to pay for removing
the tracking (sounds funny when I say it that way, no?). Goddamn I hate
tracking-by-default. Maybe I will end up setting up my own postfix with some
mailman. Or use something? If you know a good free software self-hosted
solution for newsletters feel free to drop me a mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how many times I saw dev add google analytics on their templates
and at the end nobody was going to check stats except for volume metrics. If
you only need volumetric data, use your web server logs! If you really need
fine metrics, why not consider using self-hosted analytics like &lt;a href=&#34;http://piwik.org&#34;&gt;Piwik&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I don&amp;rsquo;t hate analytics. What bothers me is what is made of
those data. Many companies chose as a business model to consider the user as a
merchandise. And most of the time they are not clear about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, one last word, next week I will prepare an option so you can chose to
receive only the links and no rant. Or only the rant and no links. Maybe I
will make each section of the letter opt-out too, if you never listen to
podcasts why should you get those, right? I just like choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Green Ruby</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2013/04/07/about-green-ruby</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2013 09:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2013/04/07/about-green-ruby</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.org/&#34;&gt;Green Ruby&lt;/a&gt; is a weekly newsletter that I’m publishing about ruby, rails, javascript and web development in general. I am preparing a website to make it more collective and here is the ‘about’ page, not yet published, but I was thinking it could be interesting to share it before the website is all ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;genesis:1c34dfda6e65228c3dbbf6fb2d30812e&#34;&gt;Genesis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Newsletter began in june 2012 from the habit I had to send weekly newsletter in &lt;a href=&#34;http://codegreenit.com/&#34;&gt;Codegreen&lt;/a&gt; for our team to know what is happening in our company,. That was purely a teamwork tool for general transparency. But with time passing I also included there some links to what I was finding around that would be of interest for my geek colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That CodeGreen Internal newsletter began to be cluttered with various links at the bottom of it. So I decided to separate that links gathering bunch in another newsletter. But then it could also be useful for my friends, out of the scope of our team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;green-birth:1c34dfda6e65228c3dbbf6fb2d30812e&#34;&gt;Green Birth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time I had to test &lt;a href=&#34;http://mailchimp.com/&#34;&gt;Mailchimp&lt;/a&gt; service for one of our projects, so because they offer a free package when volume is not too big, I thought I should just create that newsletter as a public freely available publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in february 2013 I sent the first Green Ruby Newsletter to 3 subscribers. Well, mostly our team :) Then it became a weekly habit, so I got a domain name for it, and organically it’s growing slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-redactor-gear:1c34dfda6e65228c3dbbf6fb2d30812e&#34;&gt;The redactor gear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codegreen paid for my &lt;a href=&#34;http://newsblur.com/&#34;&gt;Newsblur&lt;/a&gt; account so I can follow a bunch of feeds. Google reader was my first tool but well, they are closing, and actually Newsblur is much better. It’s open source and the guy that makes it does a great job (too bad it’s in python and not in ruby).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also loading a bunch of podcasts on my phone and after having tried a lot of podcast softwares I’m really happy with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.podkicker.com/&#34;&gt;Podkicker&lt;/a&gt;, it’s just very convenient and it has all I need with the free version. So in my 40 minutes commuting to go to work, I just get the ears busy. I tried to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gpodder.net/user/mose&#34;&gt;Gpodder&lt;/a&gt; but it’s not totally perfect and the support in podcast clients is not as good as it should be. So I don’t stick on it, maybe it will evolve and I will get back to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I also get a lot of news by just wandering around on &lt;a href=&#34;https://geekli.st/&#34;&gt;Geekli.st&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&#34;https://coderbits.com/&#34;&gt;Coderbits&lt;/a&gt;, hacker news, and I subscribed to a bunch of various newsletters. I also watch teh new gems feeds from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/RubyGemsAlt&#34;&gt;@rubygems-alt&lt;/a&gt; and I retweet stuff of interest on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cogtw&#34;&gt;@cogtw&lt;/a&gt; account (those 2 are my alternate twitter identities).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each week &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tubaxenor&#34;&gt;William&lt;/a&gt; (aka xenor) also sends me a list of links. But I definitely don’t use any facebook feeds. For some reason, this is a place I avoid the most I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-next:1c34dfda6e65228c3dbbf6fb2d30812e&#34;&gt;What next ?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ambition there is to keep it non-commercial, and change it to be more community driven. The preparation of the letter is eating a big part of my saturdays for the last 13 weeks and I don’t think I can keep up the same pace for long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea I have about the community driven thing is by engineering some automation on the news gathering (to replace newsblur), have a place where the news can be triaged by various people, a little bit like it is on &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/&#34;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; with a vote system. But the gathering won’t limit to blog posts and rss feeds, there would also be podcasts and video feeds. There is now a lot of possibilities in automation on feeds aggregation. I worked on a project that already does that feeds aggregation, named “the Blux”. And I expect to replicate parts of it for my Green Ruby Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also, as usual, this project is also an occasion to play with recent technologies or stuff I want to know more about, otherwise where is the fun ? So here comes &lt;a href=&#34;http://emberjs.com/&#34;&gt;Ember.js&lt;/a&gt;, on the top of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&#34;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mongodb.org/&#34;&gt;mongoDB&lt;/a&gt;, and there will be much more on the road (thinking about trying &lt;a href=&#34;http://af83.github.io/sponges/&#34;&gt;Sponges&lt;/a&gt; too).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>