<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grenruby on Moselog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mose.com/tags/grenruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grenruby on Moselog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 22:10:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.mose.com/tags/grenruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 145</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/11/15/greenruby-145</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/11/15/greenruby-145</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-about-bullies:7d0bd163d3b6e38d12756fdafb7e56e1&#34;&gt;More about bullies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I read the &lt;a href=&#34;http://devblog.avdi.org/2015/11/09/software-bullying/&#34;&gt;reaction of Avdi&lt;/a&gt; to the rant of Linus last
week. He proposes a short but insightful angle by just naming it &amp;lsquo;bullying&amp;rsquo;.
It rejoins the damage that I consider the coder-hero culture brings to our
industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly the creative process of writing software attract creative people.
They have strong personalities, some have tendencies to mild autism. They move
mountains and their pride make them work day and night to achieve unbelievable
things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is good and well, but on the long run, now that we are passing 2
generations of coders, we know that it&amp;rsquo;s not sustainable on the long run.
Plus, it has a disastrous impact on team building. No pyramid was built by a
single hero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally I also read an interesting article about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.businessinsider.com/why-computer-programmers-need-to-stop-calling-themselves-engineers-already-2015-11&#34;&gt;Why computer
programmers need to stop calling themselves engineers already&lt;/a&gt;.
Even if I can&amp;rsquo;t clearly explain how this is related, I have the feeling it&amp;rsquo;s
talking about something that is in the same area.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 144</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/11/08/greenruby-144</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/11/08/greenruby-144</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;packaging-a-gem-for-debian:2e8a1de1525658978fef3574497ed77d&#34;&gt;Packaging a gem for Debian&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I had to package a gem for debian as a .deb. As a matter of fact,
there is a lot of companies that are not in the ruby ecosystem and they rely
on things they trust rather than rubygems. For a while debian was way behind
on the inclusion of ruby and versions were outdated there. So a parallel
distribution ecosystem had to be created. Now we have rvm, rbenv, or chruby
for ruby and bundler and rubygems for the packages. But where I work, they
package everything as debian packages. So I had to adapt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went have a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.debian.org/Teams/Ruby&#34;&gt;the debian ruby team&lt;/a&gt; and checked out
the tools. That gem2deb tool is pretty convenient. I am using debian for a
while but never really had to package anything. The debian community process
is a bit complicated and they are not very inclusive. Compared to the ease of
uploading any gem to rubygems, it&amp;rsquo;s quite a fortress, and people in the
process are not very welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s generational. Debian started before sourceforge existed, they are
rooted in a community tradition that are very exclusive and a bit elitist. But
technology changes faster than people, obviously. Younger communities
bootstrap in a more fluid environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it is related but maybe it is, there was another epic [Linus
Hit][liushit] recently. Well, all those things put in perspective the niceness
of the ruby community. Really, cherish it and enjoy it, it&amp;rsquo;s precious.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 143</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/11/01/greenruby-143</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/11/01/greenruby-143</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-power-of-dsl:ab3ba7ed22eeaa19b0cb56ca8c01c80b&#34;&gt;The power of DSL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was playing with &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zetachang/react.rb&#34;&gt;react.rb&lt;/a&gt; and exploring &lt;a href=&#34;http://opalrb.org/&#34;&gt;opal&lt;/a&gt;, I
felt in a totally different world. The power of the DSL already prove its
shine on various occasions. I got to experience it in activeadmin, rspec, and
puppet (but I kind of dislike the one in puppet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m also writing some python, I can see a real difference in expressibility
that can be found in ruby. Really, ruby is a maker tool. Like a toolbox for
making new programming languages, using meta-programming, lambda and other
goodies. This is what, in my opinion, makes ruby unique. Beyond the elegance
of its syntax, it empowers developers with the ability to write dedicated
programming language for any specific use. And this, I didn&amp;rsquo;t find in python.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 142</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/10/25/greenruby-142</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/10/25/greenruby-142</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dst-sucks:30c8323f12e415f49a8e753e970d1ab8&#34;&gt;DST sucks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week-end they changed time in France. As I work with those guys to cover
the watching of servers, then I need to change time too. This is totally lame.
In the context of largely distributed teams, DST is heresy. It happens in the
US too, but not even at the same time. Man I hate DST. I&amp;rsquo;m happy we don&amp;rsquo;t have
that in Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;thunderbird-sucks-too:30c8323f12e415f49a8e753e970d1ab8&#34;&gt;Thunderbird sucks too&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the respect I have for mozilla products and for their efforts toward
the community, I have to say that I have been using thunderbird for a while
and I don&amp;rsquo;t like it. There is some lack of customability in there, it eats a
whole lot of memory and it&amp;rsquo;s kinda slow sometimes. I have been considering
getting back to mutt, which is a totally different category of mail client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.claws-mail.org/&#34;&gt;claws&lt;/a&gt;, and trying it for a few days on my various
mailboxes with hundreds of thousands of mails, and it is a very good feeling.
It&amp;rsquo;s much more transparent and hackable and stays in the same category of the
clickable mail client as thunderbird. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I will stick to claws,
maybe I will get back to mutt that I have been used so many years before. But
I sure will give that &amp;lsquo;email client that bites&amp;rsquo; a try for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gmail-sucks-more:30c8323f12e415f49a8e753e970d1ab8&#34;&gt;Gmail sucks more&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still can&amp;rsquo;t figure out why people use gmail for reading their mail. I mean,
you leave management of your mail to google, you know what they do with it.
You also want to give them information about how you read your mail? I mean,
using a webmail, first, should be a fallback. But it&amp;rsquo;s mystery for nobody that
google business is in profiling people. It blasts me how people can trust them
blindly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 140</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/10/11/greenruby-140</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/10/11/greenruby-140</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;slack-overflow:94c85cedf808f313200328bd388deb80&#34;&gt;Slack overflow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay I reckon I&amp;rsquo;m very old school. I began on the net with irc and I still stick to it. I have been confused by the trend that make people use Twitter like if it was some kind of real-time interactive medium. I have watched skype becoming unavoidable, and despicable. I hope &lt;a href=&#34;https://telegram.org/&#34;&gt;Telegram&lt;/a&gt; will kill it, honestly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been using hipchat and slack for work. Hipchat was really cool, but slack came later on and seemed more modern and featurefull. But it didn&amp;rsquo;t have a linux client for a while. So I didn&amp;rsquo;t really played much with it. But now there is a linux client, and it seems that there is an ecosystem nuilding up around slack. As they don&amp;rsquo;t charge for normal usage until you need many integrations with various services, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty easy for anyone to create some new slack team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slack was first designed for teams, and those teams are gathered by invite only. But there are many ways to smooth it up to create some open discussion area that could be compared to irc. But in a way that it includes features that on irc I had to settle myself. For example for sharing code on irc you typically use some pastebin, jsfiddle, or other service of the same kind. In slack code can be pasted in directly or uploaded as a file. For keeping some kind of permanence I always use weechat in a screen on a remote server. That way I never disconnect form irc and I can backlog when I get back. But this is not for everybody and slack has the same kind of feature. But the most noticeable feature in slack is the mobile integration. It beats irc without a doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given those benefits, various communities begin to switch from irc to slack. There are even people building up a business creating communities on slack. Check &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slacklist.info/&#34;&gt;slacklist&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://chats.directory/&#34;&gt;chat directory&lt;/a&gt;. Some of those slack teams are open, some others are accessible after a review process, some others you have to pay a fee to access them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would not say that slack replaces irc, to be honest, even if it fulfills some similar goal. It&amp;rsquo;s a totally different beast. Plus, that&amp;rsquo;s a third party that keeps all your logs. If security of your content is an issue, you should rather have an internal irc server or try an open source self-hosted slack alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I got 6 groups on my slack client, including the &lt;a href=&#34;https://greenruby.slack.com/&#34;&gt;Greenruby slack group&lt;/a&gt;. You can ask for an invite at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:news@greenruby.org&#34;&gt;slack@greenruby.org&lt;/a&gt; it&amp;rsquo;s totally open.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 136</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/09/13/greenruby-136</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/09/13/greenruby-136</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rubyconf-tw:6a0e12fe1d32b33b0719139f3561d417&#34;&gt;Rubyconf TW&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these last 2 days we went to RubyConfTW here in Taipei, like every year. At
that occasion I kinda forced my buddies to take part in this rant section. So,
that occasion of meeting the ruby community was as usual very enjoyable. Year
after year we see the same people, the community is solid and persistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like last years Matz was here and he talked about ruby 3 and, that was a
surprise to me, he talked about getting rid of the GIL very soon. That GIL
topic has been a taboo for so many years. Getting rid off it can change the
position of ruby in the family of the major scripting languages. He also
defined laziness as one of the 3 required characteristics of a good coder. I&amp;rsquo;m
not sure there is anything mainstream about those 3 qualities but for a long
time I had my set of 3 requirements to evaluate a good coder and laziness was
in it. maybe I will develop more about it in another rant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this conference I also had the occasion to hear a lot of direct
feedback from friends of Green Ruby. For example we have an irc channel but
many people are not that comfortable with that chat system from another
century and would prefer a slack room. As a matter of fact we have such a
room, but we forgot about it for the past year. It&amp;rsquo;s alive again, feel free to
send a request for invite to news at greenruby.org to join
&lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.slack.com&#34;&gt;http://greenruby.slack.com&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s open to everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rubyconftw-by-xenor:6a0e12fe1d32b33b0719139f3561d417&#34;&gt;Rubyconftw by xenor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey I&amp;rsquo;m xenor and this is my first rant in Green Ruby News about (and not
about) &lt;a href=&#34;http://2015.rubyconf.tw/&#34;&gt;rubyconftw&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work in a ruby shop and manage a couple of people, and I am recently feeling
burned-out. It affects motivation and productivity. I am in a position which
involves watching over colleagues output. But I also have my own coding
projects ongoing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first it&amp;rsquo;s great and challenging. But after half a year, it starts to bite
me back. I get tired and anxious about not meeting my goal at the end of the
day while checking others progress. I also need more breaks than usual. The
typical burn-out syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rubyconf gave me a break so that I can rethink what I was doing and how I can
evaluate things around me. During the conference, I found some time to do
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tubaxenor/squeezer&#34;&gt;side project&lt;/a&gt;. This really helps and re-motivates me on programming
(I believe this could be called &amp;lsquo;Conference Driven Development&amp;rsquo;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might wonder why I didn&amp;rsquo;t say anything about the talks. Actually, talks
are just as great as all other conferences, and can be watched on the
recordings that they will post soon. But the most important part is really the
atmosphere of encouragement to try and learn something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rubyconftw-by-tysliu:6a0e12fe1d32b33b0719139f3561d417&#34;&gt;Rubyconftw by tysliu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greetings. This is tysliu and this is also my first rant and my experience
from going to 2015 Rubyconf TW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main benefit from attending rubyconf this year is that I said hello to
more people. I met past colleagues and also new people. It feels nice to see
familiar faces and catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most interesting talk for me this years was tenderlove&amp;rsquo;s talk. It was
about how he attacked the issue of making Rails HTTP2 friendly. Basically,
Rails at the moment is not http2 compatible. This is due the the current
architecture of Rails and implementation of rack middlewares. During the talk
he was able to demo a prototype Rails that is H2 friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best news for Rails developers is that there are plans to for making HTTP
2 compatibility available in Rails 5.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 135</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/09/06/greenruby-135</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/09/06/greenruby-135</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meet-at-rubyconf:5c5ed19a98630bcf79414a52c93d484e&#34;&gt;Meet at rubyconf&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next friday we will be at &lt;a href=&#34;http://2015.rubyconf.tw/&#34;&gt;rubyconf Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;. Last year there was
around 300 attendees and there is 256 this year. But maybe there will be more
last minute registration, there is still some &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubytaiwan.kktix.cc/events/rubyconftw2015&#34;&gt;spots available&lt;/a&gt; (well
just 14 at this time). I will also be at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubytaiwan.kktix.cc/events/850d36b0&#34;&gt;pre-conf evening&lt;/a&gt; on
wednesday. Good time to meet if you are in Taiwan (we have 37 subscribers
there).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-stats-on-greenruby:5c5ed19a98630bcf79414a52c93d484e&#34;&gt;Some stats on greenruby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time I check an export of the subscribers list and do some stats
out of curiosity. As of today there are 1466 subscribers, and more than half
in the US (844) all the rest are in 88 other countries (most in India, UK,
France and Taiwan, in that order). In the US most people are from New-York,
just a little more than Los Angeles, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monticello,_Kentucky&#34;&gt;Monticello&lt;/a&gt; in Kentucky.
I wonder what there is so special in that city of less than 10k people. Maybe
that&amp;rsquo;s a geo-location glitch? If not, please someone tell me what there is in
that small and probably nice city. But if I had to bet, I would put my money
on the glitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every week there is a small number of new subscribers, especially during
summer. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t really read or if you don&amp;rsquo;t care that much, please
unsubscribe. I will certainly have to do some invitation to unsubscribe when
we will reach around 2000, because mailchimp if free of charge only under that
limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a lot of unaccounted subscribers to the RSS feed, which is the
most popular page on the website. But I don&amp;rsquo;t use feedburner or any kind of
tracking so I don&amp;rsquo;t really know. And I kind of like it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>