<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Freebsd on Moselog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mose.com/tags/freebsd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Freebsd on Moselog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 12:10:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.mose.com/tags/freebsd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a taste of FreeBSD</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/06/28/a-taste-of-freebsd</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/06/28/a-taste-of-freebsd</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I installed &lt;a href=&#34;http://freebsd.org&#34;&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt; 10.1 on a disk of my desktop.
Beyond the fact that we are using that system at work, more and more, I was
just curious about the setup for a desktop. I was pleasantly surprised and
everything went very smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m quite familiar with Linux and that was enough for making the ride very
easy. The general impression is that actually the system is simpler than on
Linux, maybe more consistent. The pkg system, alternative to the traditional
ports system, makes thing much more &amp;lsquo;out of the box&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for the rest, well, in one afternoon, and just by following the doc, I had
my window manager up and running, and ready to begin playing with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.freebsd.org/bhyve&#34;&gt;bhyve&lt;/a&gt;. I was surprised to see that bhyve kernel modules were included
by default in recent releases. I heard there are still some bumps on the road
for laptop about the sleep to disk mode, but I&amp;rsquo;m not concerned by that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels like BSD is a shy actor that actually powers much more stuff that we
can suspect. But it has a pretty active community and a very decent
documentation. Well, give it a try if you like playing with various
distributions of free and open operating systems. It&amp;rsquo;s much less scary that
its reputation seems to convey.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About blogging</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/03/08/about-blogging</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/03/08/about-blogging</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well, since that whole blogging thing began, I never have been very active on
it. Well, I have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.mose.com&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; on Tumblr because I wanted to know how they
are doing it, I published various posts in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://devtips.faria.co/authors.html#mose-ref&#34;&gt;faria devtips&lt;/a&gt;, and
after all, this rant could also count as a publication. So I think I will
gather them all under one unique site. A Jekyll github-pages kind, easy and
cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure the devtips website will stay up any longer. There
have been no post since the day I left. Too bad. It&amp;rsquo;s a demonstration that
some collective actions can sometimes rely only on the energy of one person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I made a &lt;a href=&#34;http://mose.github.io/blog&#34;&gt;new repo&lt;/a&gt; on github for it, and I will gather whatever
stuff I can find that I wrote in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lovely-freebsd:111d43eaf8a2a6adad496f0417e7f52c&#34;&gt;Lovely FreeBSD&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At our Gandi office in Taipei I had to install a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pfsense.org/&#34;&gt;pfsense&lt;/a&gt; server,
which is based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freebsd.org/&#34;&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt;. It was quite a pleasant experience,
actually. Last time I played a bit with BSD that was 12 years ago, and that
was not very smooth. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to be given that occasion to see how it goes
now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now I&amp;rsquo;m going to use it like if it was an &lt;a href=&#34;https://openwrt.org/&#34;&gt;OpenWRT&lt;/a&gt; with some
extra &lt;a href=&#34;https://openvpn.net/index.php/open-source.html&#34;&gt;OpenVPN&lt;/a&gt; abilities. And it will also be a file server for the
LAN. Not sure yet how I will handle that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ruby-package-management:111d43eaf8a2a6adad496f0417e7f52c&#34;&gt;Ruby package management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got in my new job, I discovered a new way to manage server management.
They didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://rvm.io/&#34;&gt;rvm&lt;/a&gt;, or even &lt;a href=&#34;https://rubygems.org/&#34;&gt;ruby gems&lt;/a&gt;, or
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pip.pypa.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;pip&lt;/a&gt; or anything that is not debian packages. It may sound quite harsh.
Since I came in ruby in 2010, rvm has been my best friend, bundle the second
one. But this approach is very developer-based. When you maintain large and
stable systems, it&amp;rsquo;s more likely that you will not trust the bleeding edge
stuff and prefer confirmed publication of packages before using them. This is
an interesting slap on my face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course there are the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brightbox.com/docs/ruby/ubuntu/&#34;&gt;brightbox&lt;/a&gt; packages for Ubuntu, but that&amp;rsquo;s
missing the point. A release has to be out for a certain time so it can be
strengthened by security reviews and proper production usage. There is a part
of the population for each language that is considering the instability of
current releases a normal trade-off. but there is a huge lot of other
companies that will wait patiently that things get stable enough for their
taste.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>