<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Moselog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mose.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Moselog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:25:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.mose.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How I came to collective intelligence</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2017/05/01/how-i-came-to-collective-intelligence</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:25:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2017/05/01/how-i-came-to-collective-intelligence</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I plan to share some thoughts about Collective Intelligence from a software perspective.
But this comes from an old story that I thought I should make public first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-origins:ea7330696100fc7495594863651b3c82&#34;&gt;The origins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first began to program web applications, it was mostly for my own needs
as an activist (freedom of speech on internet, cryptography, and such matters).
Around 1998 I had a fully working solution called &amp;lsquo;Collaborative writer&amp;rsquo; or
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/cwriter/&#34;&gt;cWriter&lt;/a&gt; for short, written in PHP. It was like a sort of wiki geared towards
small groups self-organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to Claranet I deployed it as an internal solution, and worked on a
full company intranet called &amp;lsquo;in&amp;rsquo;. It was the occasion to release cWriter as
open source in 2000 on Sourceforge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time it appeared obvious that my area of preference was about engineering
collaborative work. I was putting a lot of thoughts into that. I had this clear
understanding that the tool shapes the usages, especially in this new realm that
was internet communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, I dedicated my time in various projects, mostly &lt;a href=&#34;https://tiki.org/mose&#34;&gt;Tikiwiki groupware&lt;/a&gt; in 2003.
That experience was also rich in valuable experiments. I became leader in that community
because being unemployed at that time, I took the occasion to just invest time in
open source (being payed by labor insurance money). And I was just very prolific.
I established various bases for that community that still thrives today. I had a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tiki.org/Webinar+2012+10&#34;&gt;recorded interview&lt;/a&gt; with the guys for the 10 years for the project in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-discovery:ea7330696100fc7495594863651b3c82&#34;&gt;The discovery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in 2004 I met with &lt;a href=&#34;http://noubel.com/&#34;&gt;JF Noubel&lt;/a&gt;, that had some need for help on his own Tikiwiki
instance, called thetransitionner.org. His website (not available anymore nowadays)
was dedicated to promotion and exploration of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collective_intelligence&#34;&gt;Collective Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;, following the work,
among others, of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pierre_L%C3%A9vy&#34;&gt;Pierre Lévy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly identified this area of research as something that I was practicing and
aiming at, without having formally identified it. So I got more and more interested
into that field in the following years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jean-Francois became a friend, his approach evolved since then but I still got stuck with
his &lt;a href=&#34;http://publishing.yudu.com/Library/Arswi/CollectiveIntelligen/resources/index.htm?skipFlashCheck=true&#34;&gt;original presentation&lt;/a&gt; describing the basics of Collective Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways it led me to some other kind of activism, revolving around some alternative currency
projects (like &lt;a href=&#34;http://openmoney.org/&#34;&gt;openmoney&lt;/a&gt;), other projects concerning governance (like democracy 2.0,
from Mikael Nordfors cited in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/stream/eo_Collective_Intelligence/Collective_Intelligence_djvu.txt&#34;&gt;transcript on archive.org&lt;/a&gt;), and various other topics
that would be too long to list here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately it led to get involved in &lt;a href=&#34;http://angenius.org/tiki-index.php&#34;&gt;Angenius&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thanh_Nghiem&#34;&gt;Than Nghiem&lt;/a&gt; in a background of
sustainable development between 2006 and 2008. Including going to live in a farm in Normandy.
Which was amazing but I was just not made for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-migration:ea7330696100fc7495594863651b3c82&#34;&gt;The migration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2008 I decided to leave France and go live in Taiwan. I wanted to take a break and
learn Chinese. It was my decision for my 40th birthday. Since then I got various jobs in
development and then in system administration, grinding more programming languages and
technical skills. But I still kept all this time the background thinking on
collective intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I wanted to experience was just another cultural background. I wanted to see patterns
a little better about open source communities and collaborative work in a different context.
Well. This could be the topic for another post. I got some surprises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-next:ea7330696100fc7495594863651b3c82&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 9 years after, I feel it&amp;rsquo;s more than time I get back to my past ventures. Well,
I didn&amp;rsquo;t live like an hermit, I&amp;rsquo;m involved in various local and global communities.
But I feel I could share a little more about what I learned in my past experiments.
Now that I reach my 50&amp;rsquo;s, maybe I just feel like I have to begin writing stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Interviews approach</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2017/04/29/the-interviews-approach</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 22:25:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2017/04/29/the-interviews-approach</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;interview-based-knowledge-sharing:1b8340b7f1acd4b3212e7dd40ccc3d0c&#34;&gt;Interview-based knowledge sharing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years I noticed the difficulty to extract decent information from
developers and craftsmen about their work. Developers clearly lack the
skill or the taste for documentation. It extends to the specifications,
which also provides an occasion to notice bad performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To work this around, specialized project managers have to fill this role,
but it can create a gap between developers ownership and the final result.
Sometimes luck creates the inspiration and developers produce a decent
amount of documentation. But honestly, this is pure luck, and not a rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a way to mitigate this issue, that I began to experiment some time
ago at work. It&amp;rsquo;s based on a recorded interaction between a project person and
a person of the craft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the project person organizes interviews with stakeholders from all specialties
including developers, business people, operations people, sometimes users,
the more diverse population possible. But it can also be done for no reason
for sharing a certain kind of knowledge with an expert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interviews take place by written interactive communication in a chat,
in a way that enables logging (irc, slack, whatever)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it lasts 20 minutes more or less, but the format can extend to hours if the need is felt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once the interview is finished, the interviewer cleans up the logs, removes out of topic
details, fixes typoes, removes elements that are purely belonging to the chat way of communication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the cleaned log is reviewed by the interviewee for consensual agreement on its publication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the log can then be added to whatever project space is dedicated to the topic at hand
(documentation, specification annexes, study, paper)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are various beneficial side effects to this endeavor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;actors have a better feeling of engagement in the project or topic at hand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it creates a bond between actors, facilitates future exchanges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it gives an equal chance for everyone to speak, even the shy ones, because the 1 to 1
context is much less frightening. In a meeting, there are people that never speak.
Are they stupid? they are not!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it creates content that can be shared with other actors so that they have a better
chance to understand the point of views of other parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it creates a useful reference for the project, a raw material which can be annexed
and can be used for summaries. It also creates more content for an eventual search engine
if the publication space has one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is less risk to cite someone out of context because the full context is provided.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is much easier to organize interviews or hold them on the fly than setup meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is no feeling of loss of time like in a meeting: the time dedicated is intense
and very interactive, there is no waste.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the occasion to try that technique in a context where internal communication is
not optimal, for knowledge sharing at first, then for exploring options on a new project
and set up specifications. I have been happy to notice that this formula creates pretty
good output and generates a nice feeling in all parties involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly more study will come on this approach. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting back into writing</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2017/04/28/getting-back-into-writing</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2017/04/28/getting-back-into-writing</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enough-sleeping:de01faa72149d30f4eb88db96f78a8dd&#34;&gt;Enough sleeping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I got tired of leading &lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.org&#34;&gt;Greenruby&lt;/a&gt;
publication and Xenor accepted to jump in and take the publisher role.
I&amp;rsquo;m very grateful about it. But as a secundary effect, I lost that ranting
channel I got used to abuse. Each week, I was getting somehow acustomed
to send some rant with the list of links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back into a publisher mood. I have various thoughts
that could deserve sharing, or at least, publication. Well I don&amp;rsquo;t tweet much
and I hate facebook, so my media coverage may be a little tiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s not really a problem. It&amp;rsquo;s not like I have some agenda.
I just wish to exercise my right to reflect aloud on various topics, bring to
the open some personal and/or original thoughts. Nothing more. Whoever reads,
do it in silence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 197</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/11/13/greenruby-197</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/11/13/greenruby-197</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-lovely-chatbots-sick-already:eae14584655a9a501cab4772b62674f0&#34;&gt;My lovely Chatbots, sick already?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I have been to a meetup about chatbots. I was expecting something
technical. But it seems that I was totally mislead on what chatbots are. They
are visibly now more of a marketing tool than just a cool piece of technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty convinced that web interfaces are going to die slowly in favor of
more conversational interfaces. But in past technology shift we had some time
between appearance and marketability. Like with the web, the social networks,
etc. No more. Chatbots are immediate slaves for sales volumes. All the
blooming of new services for &amp;lsquo;building your own bot&amp;rsquo; are just totally geared
towards customers management and acquisition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My naive assumption was that assistive conversational interface could have a
larger scope. But well, the market is driven by what sells, and what sells is
what make more sales. I just hope it will have a nice border effect to improve
chatbots as a tool or as a general interface to access information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my instinct warns me against the potential invasion of our social world
online by all sort of aggressive automated peddlers. The same way we get
robotic phone calls. Chatbots are going to be the new color of spam?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 193</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/10/16/greenruby-193</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/10/16/greenruby-193</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-facebook-the-new-npm:33c6cbaaffa1f33ba49e5064e8787b21&#34;&gt;Is Facebook the new NPM?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week there is a lot of noise in the JS ecosystem, on various trends. But
the most noticeable is about &lt;a href=&#34;https://yarnpkg.com/&#34;&gt;Yarn&lt;/a&gt;. Yet another package manager for js,
that states it opens a war against NPM (in soft terms but clearly enough). The
&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.facebook.com/posts/1840075619545360&#34;&gt;long post from Facebook&lt;/a&gt; about it demonstrates a clear effort to push
things forward about NPM shortcomings. The reaction on &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=12684980&#34;&gt;hacker news&lt;/a&gt;
is pretty verbose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It provoked a public &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.npmjs.org/post/151660845210/hello-yarn&#34;&gt;response from NPM&lt;/a&gt; to try to explain that, nop,
it&amp;rsquo;s not a war. But I keep feeling that Facebook is slowly taking over another
piece of the javascript world. For now, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem harmful at all, but my
instinct lights a various number of warning bonfires.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for real, it was more than time that the supremacy of NPM was questioned.
It has a lot of flaws and the number of posts about this event proves that the
community was kind of waiting for something like this to happen. Like this
&lt;a href=&#34;https://shift.infinite.red/npm-vs-yarn-cheat-sheet-8755b092e5cc#.d5wnp2yf9&#34;&gt;cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt;, various articles like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoworld.com/article/3130179/javascript/facebook-spins-yarn-to-replace-npm-packager.html&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;, this
enthusiastic post from &lt;a href=&#34;http://yehudakatz.com/2016/10/11/im-excited-to-work-on-yarn-the-new-js-package-manager-2/&#34;&gt;Yehuda Kats&lt;/a&gt;. But &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@boennemann/questions-i-wish-yarn-had-answered-on-day-1-ec0db7458107#.r1kyqfnwr&#34;&gt;not everybody is happy&lt;/a&gt;
about how things are done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I like the technical direction it takes. But I hope that like
io.js went back to node.js, it will eventually merge back to NPM, really. But
I have the feeling it is not going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 192</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/10/09/greenruby-192</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/10/09/greenruby-192</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-js-toolback-hell:151a80b7575169c1b4c5c3e795aacfee&#34;&gt;The JS toolback hell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I laughed a lot while reading &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/how-it-feels-to-learn-javascript-in-2016-d3a717dd577f#.pl6hx94d3&#34;&gt;How it feels to learn JavaScript in
2016&lt;/a&gt;. That article had a pretty &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macwright.org/2016/10/04/everything-is-fine-with-javascript.html&#34;&gt;good response&lt;/a&gt;, like it hits a
nerve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But seriously it&amp;rsquo;s clear that we are at a transition time in Javascript
evolution, and there is a huge chaos of possible alternatives to everything.
It feels like an ecosystem where the natural selection didn&amp;rsquo;t operate its
magic yet. It&amp;rsquo;s like there are things in suspension that are going to fall in
order at some point eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal bet is that things like elm will win the race, because with its
embrace of functional programming it seems like it opens the door to
interpretation with yet-to-be-written faster and more direct compilers (rather
than transpiling to js). But that&amp;rsquo;s just a hunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the while, front-end craft is now a wizard arcane art. It can&amp;rsquo;t be acquired
by pure reasoning and logic, or reading a doc. You need the map of the
landscape for knowing the possible choices and alternative intermediary
solutions. For part-time front-end people, it&amp;rsquo;s just hell. For now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 191</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/10/02/greenruby-191</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/10/02/greenruby-191</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-m-in-holidays:b1244f7eff2aad7b5fd0625537cc8e0a&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in holidays&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great occasion to kick thunderbird byebye and spend some time on configuring
my mutt to make it real again, after 6 years of click-click for mail. I was a
mutt user for a very long time, and my pause for trying a GUI mail client just
had to have an end. But the mail has clearly become something else now.
Actually much more volume, but much more automated things, and news feeds. Or
it&amp;rsquo;s just me?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 190</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/09/25/greenruby-190</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/09/25/greenruby-190</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-stress-free-life:210225183e37db0ce5a2649da43cbec4&#34;&gt;A stress-free life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next friday, I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that I have to stop working for 2 weeks. Well, for
people that have a normal life and/or kids, it&amp;rsquo;s a pretty good news. For
people that get heavy pressure from their work, it can give some air. But I
wondered why I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I ever felt the need for holidays. I take them
by principle, but I&amp;rsquo;m usually not really eager to get them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some consideration, it all sums up to some kind of discipline. I refuse
stress on a daily basis. I want each day at work to be enjoyable and
debt-free. It&amp;rsquo;s a bad news for some category of employers. The same way those
consider it&amp;rsquo;s acceptable to accumulate technical debt, they apply the same
principle on human-life debt. Put people under pressure, get a loan on their
health, that will never be repaid. So, I just refuse pressure, the same way I
would refuse to eat meat if I was really vegetarian (which I am only
part-time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really I have more trouble with holidays because they bring a gap in the
continuity of work. You get back and there is a lot to catch up on. I would
prefer to have just one hour work less per day than week-long breaks. But
that&amp;rsquo;s just me. It would be totally different if I wanted to travel for fun or
if I had kids. My case is not reproducible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the baseline remains valid. whether you have plans or not for holidays,
they should not be required for having a balanced life. Stress has to be
fought on a daily basis and not by using breaks. Breaks, in such case, are
even more enjoyable, if you have the context for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way I know to push stress away is to put my efforts into what I do,
in a way that I&amp;rsquo;m self-aware that I&amp;rsquo;m really doing what I can to fulfill my
duties. If someone is not happy about the output, that&amp;rsquo;s their problem not
mine. If it leads to some awkward context, then it&amp;rsquo;s broken and I will reach
out to find a better work context. I apply that principle for more than 20
years now and I can&amp;rsquo;t remember last time I felt stressed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 189</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/09/18/greenruby-189</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/09/18/greenruby-189</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-learning:25cf5a2664fd7aa4f4e5aff03248e656&#34;&gt;The art of learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my review this week I read that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2016/09/14/Old-Geek&#34;&gt;Old Geek post&lt;/a&gt;, which has a lot
of comments under its feet. This is quite interesting. But I feel there is a
confusion here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my experience, age is often related to stagnation. The more you
accumulate, the heavier you are. It&amp;rsquo;s heart-breaking to abandon years of
investment in one type of knowledge. Therefore, generally speaking, older
people are less flexible and less likely to surf on the waves of the new
technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I can tell you as a fact that this is just a natural human law, that, like
many others, can be bended. Bended by discipline, the same way we overcome our
animal instincts. There are many old practitioners of our skill that became
master in the art of change. The sacred art of eternal learning. The wisdom of
daily questioning of previously acquired knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obsolescence is not a question of age, but just a question of personality,
environment and priorities. I know a handful of such oldgeeks that didn&amp;rsquo;t yet
reach their 30&amp;rsquo;s. And personally (in my 49), I won&amp;rsquo;t stop surfing any time
soon. hahaha.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 188</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/09/11/greenruby-188</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/09/11/greenruby-188</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;observability-and-digestibility:a97c278ef841935dd0d0e1b0e41782ad&#34;&gt;Observability and Digestibility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a word I love. I found it again in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/production-ready/systems-blindness-and-how-we-deal-with-it-d601fa63b7f4#.ub69zflcv&#34;&gt;recent blog post about system blindness&lt;/a&gt;
and it reminded me how critical this need is. Our
systems get more and more numerous and small. The reliability and debugging of
a platform now goes into various loops given the multiplication of actors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Observability should be one core pre-requisite when designing a service
oriented architecture with micro-services. But just having everything plugged
to some ELK is not going to help that much. I feel that there is a new job in
there. Some function that has to be fulfilled. Something to reduce that vast
amount of data into something that makes sense. An intermediary that will
correlate logs from various sources. It would put them together and reduce
them to some meaningful &amp;lsquo;events&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think observability is not enough. Digestibility is what makes
observability worth it. Maybe such tools already exist? Hmm, probably in the
containers worlds there is something like that. Is there not?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 187</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/09/04/greenruby-187</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/09/04/greenruby-187</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-out:7741c696b47b149abfe2c5fda320314d&#34;&gt;Get out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you only ever have lived in only one country, you really should consider
fixing it. Going &lt;a href=&#34;https://inassets1-internationsgmbh.netdna-ssl.com/static/bundles/internationsexpatinsider/pdf/expat_insider_2016_the_internations_survey.pdf&#34;&gt;live in another country&lt;/a&gt; for some years or more is just
such a way towards a richer life. It&amp;rsquo;s usually easy to recognize people that
are multi-rooted, as they often have an increased depth in their personal
philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are lucky, in our craft, to have various opportunities to travel and work
remotely, or for foreign companies. Many of you are already aware of those
benefits. But to the others I can just say this: use this opportunity! Get
out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 186</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/08/28/greenruby-186</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/08/28/greenruby-186</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-be-remote-or-not-to-be-remote:1376d8ec44d87fc0206977e0453baca2&#34;&gt;To be remote or not to be remote &amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this week I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/do-work-from-home-oleg-vishnepolsky&#34;&gt;an article on linkedin, deliberately
anti-remote&lt;/a&gt;, and a bit later on &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/the-economics-of-working-remotely-28d4173e16e2#.43ewevr3t&#34;&gt;another one very pro-remote on
freecodecamp&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m tempted to think one is the response to the other. But
maybe not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is that switching to a remote organization is a tricky move. It feels
like the move from monolith to micro-services, honestly. People that make
decisions about it rarely envision the extent of the change. And those change
look similar in nature. Team architecture and software design are not that
foreign. More autonomy for services or people, self-contained activity,
requirement for clear communication channels and protocols, extensive
architecture for monitoring, reporting or just plain visibility, more
debugging tools and processes, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same way one will have to think about all those when switching to
microservices, the one that thinks about making his team remote will also have
to consider the exact same parameters. But that is all on the principles.
About the implementation, remote teams really need a strong chat culture, an
easy and transparent logging policy for all communication channels, various
tooling similar to chatops tools for assisting communication activity. Remote
organization also need to have all their processes online, and not need much
(if at all) any synchronous meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my perspective there are various very beneficial side-effects to make a
team remote. There is more traceability as everything is online and not in
corridors anymore. In some cases that I experienced, it also leads to a less
arbitrary perception on team members, because they can be judged more on
results (if you have measure tools prepared accordingly) than on attitude and
mouth-skills (did you noticed that irl meetings are sometimes just a
mouth-o-cracy?). But it&amp;rsquo;s accurate to say that on a short term, it is more
time consuming. The real benefit rises on the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I didn&amp;rsquo;t find in any articles on the matter, is the life-cycle dimension.
A software project has a life expectancy, from a business point of view. It&amp;rsquo;s
the same game as with the technical debt. It is acceptable business-wise to
live at credit for a time, until a certain milestone. A lot of projects are
just extended MVPs intended to convince big money that they could deserve some
attention. For such project, you want very fast paced environment. It&amp;rsquo;s easier
to coerce your &lt;s&gt;slaves&lt;/s&gt; employees to go above and beyond the
expectations, when in a physical environment. This is a disposable context,
and you can skip team debt as much as technical debt. And you really need
physicality for that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I would say, if a company is not making the move towards remote
organization, maybe there are very good reasons for that. But I will be very
cautious to understand what are the real reasons. They may stink. And if they
are remote, but they just came to it recently, I would be careful about the
tooling they prepared for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 185</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/08/21/greenruby-185</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/08/21/greenruby-185</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-out:1ea5a5016d2b050f17a7e1c15a7c459b&#34;&gt;Working out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the past year I have been doing some working out. No no there is no
fitbit involved. Are you crazy? My physical activity includes a strict refusal
of pointless efforts. I deliberately choose to use the bike rather than the
bus, it has the purpose of transportation,. But just getting sweaty for the
sake of it, well, that&amp;rsquo;s not my thing. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about a git-commit working
out. I decided to have one commit a day on github (minimum) and instead of the
fitbit or whatever phone app, I used the github timeline as a monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s one year now and I got my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mose/&#34;&gt;github
timeline&lt;/a&gt; all green. In itself it doesn&amp;rsquo;t achieve
anything except for myself. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy to fill up a timeline with
fake entries. But by getting this challenge of one commit a day, it led to
some valuable outcomes. I got some more work projects validated to be
published as open source. Whenever I was not feeling inspired for code commit,
I was chasing typoes in my Readme&amp;rsquo;s, or dependencies upgrades in my gems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it had quite a good impact on my coding publication, on the updating
of my blog (well, that blpg mostly gather the rants I do here), and various
other small details. Well, I&amp;rsquo;m not a very famous open source coder, just an
average joe. But a persistent one. It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to just upload shit on
github and forget about it. Having this regular commitment made me come back
on some old things, keep them current somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting some routine in place that includes open source activity has various
benefits, even when you don&amp;rsquo;t have an audience. You should try it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 183</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/08/07/greenruby-183</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/08/07/greenruby-183</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-reign-of-the-virtual:161a22387a1160601decdc89dcca85bc&#34;&gt;The reign of the virtual&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday morning, the hunt for Pokemons opened here in Taiwan. I have been
watching the crazy adoption of this new trend in the past few weeks. And
knowing the asian culture, I suspect Japan and Taiwan are going to make the
craziness in the rest of the world just like mild interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are few occasions to notice a huge shift in civilization as clearly as
this one. For sure we have noticed that our fellow human neighbors spend more
and more time the nose on their mobile devices. But this pokemon enthusiasm
bring it to a whole new level. It proves the virtual now begins to overrule
the real in term of social conventions. Well, not for everybody, not
everywhere, but in a proportion that is relevant enough to be noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real world always have been ruling the social activities. Laws and
conventions were deciding who is in and who is out, what to do and how to do
it right. This is going to change. My main concern is that the future of the
social activity is in the hands of private companies. Those companies,
legitimately driven by profit, consider the user as a resource, that requires
gathering and retention strategies. Like herds. The whole privacy fight is not
going to stand too long as cattle (oops I meant user) data is the 21st century
gold, and economy (and crazy need for constant growth) depends on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;m not really happy from this deduction. We are getting captured with
advanced weapons generated by behavioral economics and other clever social
sciences. They are manipulation tools. Just tools. Sure you can do good with
them, but such powerful tools of mass manipulation are not going to stay
neutral in the hands of those who want to squeeze our essence (feels like a
matrix metaphor, yeah I&amp;rsquo;m aware of it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our mobile devices become interfaces now. Direct access to our behaviors. They
already have been great tracking and data collection devices for years. Now
they begin to be manipulative with much more effectiveness. Sure, the pokemon
hunting doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to harm much, but I see it as only a beginning, a
trigger. It just makes sense. Everybody can see the success it has. Certainly
there are already hundreds of projects that are seeing the light right now at
this instant just under the visibility of that opportunity. And many of those
will be clever, engaging, and impacting on the real world, by the way of
mobile devices, the reverse-remote-control for getting a grip on every human
being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I&amp;rsquo;m an old guy, I&amp;rsquo;m of course very worried about this future. I have
memories of a past where it was so much different. But the young generations,
seeing this as the norm, will just fall for it, without question. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me
wrong, I love good tools that can make our lives easier. But they are tools.
The intent of their usage matters. Augmented reality just seems to be going to
be used with very nefarious intents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hrum. Well yeah, this is a rant, that&amp;rsquo;s nothing more. Not an essay, not a
study. Just my guts getting spread over the table. Take it easy :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 182</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2016/07/30/greenruby-182</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2016/07/30/greenruby-182</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chatops-and-machine-learning:e9b36217e79099e03b1370ffadd11329&#34;&gt;Chatops and machine learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I slowly becomes the chatops specialist where I work, I get to think I
want more. Since the beginning we have been interacting with programs
essentially with graphical interfaces. First asynchronous if we think about
the web, now more and more synchronous, but they are interfaces that are not
human. They are designed for giving control to the operators of those
interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the more we advance in autonomy of our programs, the more we should trust
them to sort the information by priorities. The interfaces like Siri, Echo,
are much more &amp;lsquo;human&amp;rsquo; and conversational. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t take a genius to
speculate that interfaces are going to die one day, except for very
specialized usages, and more interaction will be just more conversational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the course of my development of interactive agents for technical needs, I
noticed that adding just a little bit of intelligence and memory in those
agents goes a long way in usability. Especially in chatops, a lot of the
actions required from those agents are predicable and repetitive. The
development of new features should follow the recognition of those patterns
and shorten the path to accomplish some actions. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But coding this continually is not very cost effective. Tools also change,
then patterns evolve. Now all I can think about is a way to design an irc bot
that learns by itself. Some program that does real meta-programming and
considers its commands as data rather than hard-coded pre-conceived path for
the information to flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know some tools that already do that, can you fire me a mail?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>