<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mose on Moselog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mose.com/tags/mose/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mose on Moselog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 20:25:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.mose.com/tags/mose/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The virtues of transitions</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2017/05/31/the-virtues-of-transitions</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 20:25:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2017/05/31/the-virtues-of-transitions</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;A collection of events occurred since my last post. I was really hoping to
get some deep dive into writing more about collective intelligence, in the background.
But various things came and distracted me from that initial trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hubot-revival:195c338923f21c367264a5b5fb00e8a9&#34;&gt;Hubot revival&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, there has been a revival of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/github/hubot&#34;&gt;Hubot project&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote a bunch of
plugins for that chatbot for internal usage at Gandi in the past year. I have been poking
around in the community complaining that it became some sort of abandonware. Issues on github
were not addressed, PR unanswered, irc was silent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then one day 3 weeks ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bkeepers&#34;&gt;bkeepers&lt;/a&gt; came up and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/github/hubot/blob/master/ROADMAP.md&#34;&gt;woke it up&lt;/a&gt;.
It appears that now Github has plan for this codebase. They want to include it in its products
more officially, says the rumor (nothing official yet). But it makes a lot of sense.
So then he gathered people that could be involved in the revival of the project. I was
contacted to join the core team. That&amp;rsquo;s what you get by nagging people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then it has been quite great to clean up backlog, re-examine old ideas, help setup
new process and tooling for community gardening. I never get tired to see how informal
communities can shape up and self-organize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quiting-is-not-a-bad-thing:195c338923f21c367264a5b5fb00e8a9&#34;&gt;Quiting is not a bad thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around the same time, I felt inspired by handing my resignation of my current job at Gandi.
There is nothing wrong with the job, and most reasonable people could argue that I&amp;rsquo;m just stupid.
But there are a combination of factors that led me to think I was not using my potential at
full capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on a large infrastructure as a sysadmin was great, but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty hard to build new things
properly in the service industry. It&amp;rsquo;s always about contingency management, and reacting to the environment.
It&amp;rsquo;s more about doing the fireman than the gardener. Well, honestly, I think it&amp;rsquo;s a question of intent
and culture and that could have been addressed. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t see any hint that could let me think this
environment would become intentional about gardening anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, out of the blue, I left. I chose a moment where there was no crisis, no trouble, no real reason
to quit except a strong feeling that it was time to move on. That way, transition is painless, there
is no frustration involved. I hate conflicts. My advice: never wait the burn out to make your move out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;green-ruby-end-of-life:195c338923f21c367264a5b5fb00e8a9&#34;&gt;Green ruby end of life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mood of transitionning, this week I proposed that we close the &lt;a href=&#34;http://greenruby.org&#34;&gt;Green Ruby&lt;/a&gt; adventure.
For some months Xenor has taken over the publication process. But he&amp;rsquo;s himself bunt out a bit.
So after 4 years of publication, it&amp;rsquo;s time to close this properly and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That weekly links collection was a fun exercise. And I&amp;rsquo;m really happy to have refused any business
side track on this operation, it would have been much harder to close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-next:195c338923f21c367264a5b5fb00e8a9&#34;&gt;What next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I could stay funemployed for a while (that&amp;rsquo;s the proper term, right?). I&amp;rsquo;m planning
to look around, play with techs, talk with friends, hold on any decision to engage in anything.
It&amp;rsquo;s time to re-assess my roadmap. This is what is great in transitions.
By losing contact with the ground, you can feel the direction of the wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I will get back to entrepreneurship, and setup some business venture. Maybe I will freelance for a while.
Maybe I will find a context in a company where I feel comfortable contributing. But honestly I have no clue.
And yet, this feels great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-back-to-old-friends:195c338923f21c367264a5b5fb00e8a9&#34;&gt;Getting back to old friends&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first days after my decision to renounce my day job, I got back in contact with a lot of old friends.
Transitions have that side effect that you have to re-evaluate your environment, your network, your values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting into a full-time job doesn&amp;rsquo;t prevent that, of course, but you cannot give the same attention.
The center of gravity of an employed person is static. Now that I&amp;rsquo;m floating, I have to dedicate much more
attention to my environment. And it&amp;rsquo;s an excellent thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will certainly have occasion to talk about my adventures very soon. Maybe I will force myself to write more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I came to collective intelligence</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2017/05/01/how-i-came-to-collective-intelligence</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:25:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2017/05/01/how-i-came-to-collective-intelligence</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I plan to share some thoughts about Collective Intelligence from a software perspective.
But this comes from an old story that I thought I should make public first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-origins:ea7330696100fc7495594863651b3c82&#34;&gt;The origins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first began to program web applications, it was mostly for my own needs
as an activist (freedom of speech on internet, cryptography, and such matters).
Around 1998 I had a fully working solution called &amp;lsquo;Collaborative writer&amp;rsquo; or
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourceforge.net/projects/cwriter/&#34;&gt;cWriter&lt;/a&gt; for short, written in PHP. It was like a sort of wiki geared towards
small groups self-organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got to Claranet I deployed it as an internal solution, and worked on a
full company intranet called &amp;lsquo;in&amp;rsquo;. It was the occasion to release cWriter as
open source in 2000 on Sourceforge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that time it appeared obvious that my area of preference was about engineering
collaborative work. I was putting a lot of thoughts into that. I had this clear
understanding that the tool shapes the usages, especially in this new realm that
was internet communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on, I dedicated my time in various projects, mostly &lt;a href=&#34;https://tiki.org/mose&#34;&gt;Tikiwiki groupware&lt;/a&gt; in 2003.
That experience was also rich in valuable experiments. I became leader in that community
because being unemployed at that time, I took the occasion to just invest time in
open source (being payed by labor insurance money). And I was just very prolific.
I established various bases for that community that still thrives today. I had a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://tiki.org/Webinar+2012+10&#34;&gt;recorded interview&lt;/a&gt; with the guys for the 10 years for the project in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-discovery:ea7330696100fc7495594863651b3c82&#34;&gt;The discovery&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in 2004 I met with &lt;a href=&#34;http://noubel.com/&#34;&gt;JF Noubel&lt;/a&gt;, that had some need for help on his own Tikiwiki
instance, called thetransitionner.org. His website (not available anymore nowadays)
was dedicated to promotion and exploration of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collective_intelligence&#34;&gt;Collective Intelligence&lt;/a&gt;, following the work,
among others, of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pierre_L%C3%A9vy&#34;&gt;Pierre Lévy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly identified this area of research as something that I was practicing and
aiming at, without having formally identified it. So I got more and more interested
into that field in the following years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jean-Francois became a friend, his approach evolved since then but I still got stuck with
his &lt;a href=&#34;http://publishing.yudu.com/Library/Arswi/CollectiveIntelligen/resources/index.htm?skipFlashCheck=true&#34;&gt;original presentation&lt;/a&gt; describing the basics of Collective Intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways it led me to some other kind of activism, revolving around some alternative currency
projects (like &lt;a href=&#34;http://openmoney.org/&#34;&gt;openmoney&lt;/a&gt;), other projects concerning governance (like democracy 2.0,
from Mikael Nordfors cited in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/stream/eo_Collective_Intelligence/Collective_Intelligence_djvu.txt&#34;&gt;transcript on archive.org&lt;/a&gt;), and various other topics
that would be too long to list here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately it led to get involved in &lt;a href=&#34;http://angenius.org/tiki-index.php&#34;&gt;Angenius&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thanh_Nghiem&#34;&gt;Than Nghiem&lt;/a&gt; in a background of
sustainable development between 2006 and 2008. Including going to live in a farm in Normandy.
Which was amazing but I was just not made for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-migration:ea7330696100fc7495594863651b3c82&#34;&gt;The migration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2008 I decided to leave France and go live in Taiwan. I wanted to take a break and
learn Chinese. It was my decision for my 40th birthday. Since then I got various jobs in
development and then in system administration, grinding more programming languages and
technical skills. But I still kept all this time the background thinking on
collective intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I wanted to experience was just another cultural background. I wanted to see patterns
a little better about open source communities and collaborative work in a different context.
Well. This could be the topic for another post. I got some surprises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-s-next:ea7330696100fc7495594863651b3c82&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, 9 years after, I feel it&amp;rsquo;s more than time I get back to my past ventures. Well,
I didn&amp;rsquo;t live like an hermit, I&amp;rsquo;m involved in various local and global communities.
But I feel I could share a little more about what I learned in my past experiments.
Now that I reach my 50&amp;rsquo;s, maybe I just feel like I have to begin writing stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>