<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perl on Moselog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mose.com/tags/perl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perl on Moselog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 22:10:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.mose.com/tags/perl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Code in the dark, perl 6</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/11/29/code-in-the-dark-perl-6</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/11/29/code-in-the-dark-perl-6</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;My attention was brought this week to &lt;a href=&#34;http://codeinthedark.com/&#34;&gt;Code in the dark events&lt;/a&gt;. It seems
pretty cool. A 15 minutes race in html and css with no preview. But the thing
that brought my attention to that format is the special editor used for those
events with a special effect on the cursor. It seems to add a really dramatic
effect on the competition. We need more ideas like that for pure geek fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-look-at-perl-6:f6454540d52b5466477bc9e3371f78a1&#34;&gt;First look at perl 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many people, Perl sounds like trauma. Because it didn&amp;rsquo;t move for a while,
when I hear something is perl code, it sounds like it&amp;rsquo;s legacy code, old and
dusty. Well, Perl 6 is going to come out for christmas and the situation may
change. Perl 6 is in the lab for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.perlfoundation.org/perl6/index.cgi?when_will_perl_6_be_released&#34;&gt;15 years&lt;/a&gt; now, it&amp;rsquo;s more than
time to get it shipped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;http://doc.perl6.org/language/5to6-nutshell&#34;&gt;first glance&lt;/a&gt;, they seem to have tried to &amp;lsquo;modernize&amp;rsquo; the language,
make it more idiomatic. It even seems it looks more like ruby, with the
replacement of arrow by dots, the optional parenthesis, better exception
handling. Well, overall, it feels cleaner. But it also seem to have some
potential to mix functional and object-oriented in an interesting way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, maybe there is going to be a second life for the old perl. It&amp;rsquo;s a breaking
version, old perl code will certainly break on the new version. So it&amp;rsquo;s almost
like a new language. For sure I will still keep ruby as my preferred language,
but I like multilingualism, so maybe I will give it a try .. again (last perl
app I wrote was 12 years ago).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>