<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grenruby on Moselog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mose.com/tags/grenruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grenruby on Moselog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 22:10:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.mose.com/tags/grenruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 135</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/09/06/greenruby-135</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 22:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/09/06/greenruby-135</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meet-at-rubyconf:5c5ed19a98630bcf79414a52c93d484e&#34;&gt;Meet at rubyconf&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next friday we will be at &lt;a href=&#34;http://2015.rubyconf.tw/&#34;&gt;rubyconf Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;. Last year there was
around 300 attendees and there is 256 this year. But maybe there will be more
last minute registration, there is still some &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubytaiwan.kktix.cc/events/rubyconftw2015&#34;&gt;spots available&lt;/a&gt; (well
just 14 at this time). I will also be at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://rubytaiwan.kktix.cc/events/850d36b0&#34;&gt;pre-conf evening&lt;/a&gt; on
wednesday. Good time to meet if you are in Taiwan (we have 37 subscribers
there).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-stats-on-greenruby:5c5ed19a98630bcf79414a52c93d484e&#34;&gt;Some stats on greenruby&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time I check an export of the subscribers list and do some stats
out of curiosity. As of today there are 1466 subscribers, and more than half
in the US (844) all the rest are in 88 other countries (most in India, UK,
France and Taiwan, in that order). In the US most people are from New-York,
just a little more than Los Angeles, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monticello,_Kentucky&#34;&gt;Monticello&lt;/a&gt; in Kentucky.
I wonder what there is so special in that city of less than 10k people. Maybe
that&amp;rsquo;s a geo-location glitch? If not, please someone tell me what there is in
that small and probably nice city. But if I had to bet, I would put my money
on the glitch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every week there is a small number of new subscribers, especially during
summer. But if you don&amp;rsquo;t really read or if you don&amp;rsquo;t care that much, please
unsubscribe. I will certainly have to do some invitation to unsubscribe when
we will reach around 2000, because mailchimp if free of charge only under that
limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a lot of unaccounted subscribers to the RSS feed, which is the
most popular page on the website. But I don&amp;rsquo;t use feedburner or any kind of
tracking so I don&amp;rsquo;t really know. And I kind of like it that way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>