<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rubyconf on Moselog</title>
    <link>http://blog.mose.com/tags/rubyconf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rubyconf on Moselog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 12:10:31 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.mose.com/tags/rubyconf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 130</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/08/02/greenruby-130</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/08/02/greenruby-130</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rubyconf-taiwan-2015:6f1441b48959350386774005adafb7a6&#34;&gt;RubyConf Taiwan 2015&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September 11 and 12 there is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://2015.rubyconf.tw/&#34;&gt;Rubyconf here in Taiwan&lt;/a&gt;. I have
been at some past editions and it&amp;rsquo;s always a good time to meet people. Because
we are close to Japan there is usually pretty good ruby core contributors from
there. We get to see Matz, father of ruby, at each edition. But this time it
seems that the organizers pulled some kind of special trick and the famous
&lt;a href=&#34;http://tenderlovemaking.com/&#34;&gt;Aaron Patterson&lt;/a&gt; will be present. And I remember having heard
&lt;a href=&#34;http://devchat.tv/ruby-rogues/149-rr-ruby-in-government-with-sarah-allen&#34;&gt;Sarah Allen on rubyrogues&lt;/a&gt; last year, it is the first time she joins
us in Taiwan too. I think both of them will bring some unique taste to this
years rubyconf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you looked for an occasion to visit Taiwan, that may be the right time. You
won&amp;rsquo;t regret it. The ruby community in Taiwan is quite active and Taiwanese
people are amazingly welcoming to westerners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, if you want to meet the 3 of us, we will all be there. Look around for
Xenor and Tysliu, the famous editors of the Green Ruby newsletter. They
tirelessly collect links and news, fresh from the week, about ruby and other
things. And if you see someone with a Gandi T-Shirt, that will probably be me.
We probably will distribute some green ruby stickers that I still have in
stock. So then we can make new ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greenruby 128</title>
      <link>http://blog.mose.com/2015/07/19/greenruby-128</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 12:10:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.mose.com/2015/07/19/greenruby-128</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rubyconf-taiwan-2015-cfp:abd434c0512885455cdb7b8467442df0&#34;&gt;RubyConf Taiwan 2015 CFP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey it&amp;rsquo;s time to give it a try, talking at a rubyconf is a great upgrade for
any coder. That rubyconf will happen on september 11-12th in Taipei. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/news/2015/07/14/rubyconftw-2015-call-for-proposals/&#34;&gt;Check it
out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nsa-on-github:abd434c0512885455cdb7b8467442df0&#34;&gt;NSA on Github&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like someone is trying to fight back a reputation of obscurity. While
they are still pushing on more invasion of privacy, they also release some
&lt;a href=&#34;http://fossbytes.com/nsa-open-sources-its-linux-based-cyber-security-tool/&#34;&gt;open source code&lt;/a&gt;. Check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NationalSecurityAgency&#34;&gt;NSA github repository&lt;/a&gt;, they
released something already. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/simp&#34;&gt;Simp&lt;/a&gt; especially has a bunch of puppet
modules, but it&amp;rsquo;s designed only for redhat kind of systems. Quite an
interesting move.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>